<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iPhone on Suburban Nerd</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/iphone/</link><description>Recent content in iPhone on Suburban Nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Onion browser - TOR on IOS</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</guid><description>The Onion Router is a internet project that aims to anonymize your traffic by routing it through a darknet with various exit points to the Internet. Normally you would have to install a browser proxy on your machine to access TOR, but now there's a browser available for the iPad and iPhone.
Of course, I had to test it by checking out the Silk Road, a much publicized "Amazon of illegal drugs"</description></item><item><title>3 reasons for the lack of updates here lately</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</guid><description>Dark Nebula Episode 2 Gravity Hook Van Helsing</description></item><item><title>How to build a offine HTML5 iphone app</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</guid><description>I need to look into this for the iusethis iPhone application. The launch time is one thing that annoys me with that app now, and this could be a good way to sort that out.</description></item><item><title>iPhone 3GS series from Aker Brygge</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-iphone-3gs-series-from-aker-brygge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-iphone-3gs-series-from-aker-brygge/</guid><description>Glass Construction by Marcus Ramberg.
Went for a quick bike ride near Aker Brygge this morning and tested the iPhone 3GS camera. I'd like a tripod mount so I can film from the bike with it. Will test out with the gorillapod and my flip mino hd.
Update: The first set I published was post-processed using adobe lightroom to give them a mood I like. For reference, I've uploaded the non-postprocessed versions as well</description></item><item><title>Tab bar or no Tab bar?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</guid><description>Interesting writeup from Justin Williams about the use of Tab Bars in iPhone development. One of his big gripes is related to the space the tabbar uses:
When I made the decision, my thinking was that the application had four separate features, so it only made sense to separate them using the tab bar. What I found as I got further into the development of the application was that the bottom tab bar was incredibly limiting for where to place extra controls.</description></item><item><title>Diary of an app store reviewer</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</guid><description>Gruber has written a brilliant guess at what must be going on inside the heads of the Apple App Store reviewers' mind. I specially enjoyed this nugget:
I could read that over and over. It’s like the voice of a robot. The voice of authority. The voice of authoritative robots.</description></item><item><title>Good advice from mr. Gruber for budding iPhone developers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</guid><description>Want to implement anti-piracy mechanisms in your new iPhone app? I agree with most these recommendations for ways of dealing with this issue. However, I think that blocking all jailbroken phones would be a big mistake.</description></item></channel></rss>