<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on marcus</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on marcus</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Promexplorer</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-19-promexplorer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-19-promexplorer/</guid><description>Introducing Promexplorer: A Tool for Prometheus Metrics Navigation As software developers, we&amp;rsquo;re constantly inundated with an immense quantity of data and metrics. The influx of information can sometimes be overwhelming, particularly when you need to sift through a multitude of metrics and labels. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely why I developed Promexplorer — a tool designed to simplify your interaction with Prometheus exporter feeds.
Simplifying Prometheus Metrics Prometheus is a staple in the open-source community, recognized for its robust metrics collection and alerting system.</description></item><item><title>Manage Hugo With Devenv</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-18-manage-hugo-with-devenv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-18-manage-hugo-with-devenv/</guid><description>Devenv is a nice tool for maintaining your dev environments, spinning up servers, adding pre-commit-commit hooks and so on. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a bit for maintaining my nix-config, as well as some work projects, so while reviving my blog from it&amp;rsquo;s slumber, I figured I could use it to improve my setup a bit.
Devenv uses direnv to install required packages when you enter the project, so we can as least use it to install Hugo.</description></item><item><title>Conference report FosDem 2023</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-02-07-fosem-2033-conference-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 14:54:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-02-07-fosem-2033-conference-report/</guid><description>I was really happy to be back in Brussels finally, after some cancelled years due to Covid. The official beer event at Delirium was still cancelled, but a bunch of us still gathered there on Friday afternoon. Was great to see old friends from the Open Source community, but I still managed to get to the ULB on Saturday morning in time for my first talk.
Saturday Drawing k8s the right way Not a mind blowing beginning, but some nice suggestions for diagramming Kubernetes clusters, like shaded boxes/color usage, creating things as zones rather than graphs with lines, and to be sparing with the official icon set, as they are very sharp.</description></item></channel></rss>