<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Post on marcus</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/post/</link><description>Recent content in Post on marcus</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 20:05:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fosdem 2025 Conference Report</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2025-02-05-fosdem-conference-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2025-02-05-fosdem-conference-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Attended Fosdem again this year and had a blast. Made a conference report for work, so figure I
might as well post it here too. :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Hugo With devenv</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2024-01-21-managing-hugo-with-devenv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2024-01-21-managing-hugo-with-devenv/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am using the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> static site generator to generate this blog. I am also using
&lt;a href="https://devenv.sh">devenv&lt;/a> to manage my development environments. This also includes the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/marcusramberg/blog/">blog&lt;/a>. This ensures I can easily build and run the blog locally, and keep up to
date with the latest Hugo version, without having to install anything on my host system. Devenv also provides easy
integration with &lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> to allow linting of the markdown files, and CI integration with
GitHub Actions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Easily Run LLMs on nixOS</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2024-01-02-easily-run-llms-on-nixos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2024-01-02-easily-run-llms-on-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the recent AI craze, it&amp;rsquo;s fun to play with local models. I like &lt;a href="https://ollama.ai/">ollama&lt;/a>,
which lets you easily download and interact with various models. Thanks to this
recently merged &lt;a href="https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/pull/277442">PR&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s now trivial to run your own ollama
service on nixos:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-nix" data-lang="nix">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>services&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>ollama&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>enable &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">true&lt;/span>;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Adding this to your host config and rebuilding is all it takes to start the service,
and you can then interact with it via the cli or rest interface. For instance to talk
to the &lt;a href="https://mistral.ai/product/">mistral&lt;/a> model, you can do:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Experiences With Homely Alarm</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-11-04-first-experiences-with-homely-alarm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-11-04-first-experiences-with-homely-alarm/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the last few years, we&amp;rsquo;ve had managed alarm service from &lt;a href="https://www.sectoralarm.no">Sector Alarm&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly
been OK, but the price has been increasing every year, and they never upgrade our components,
so when I learned about the offering from &lt;a href="https://homely.no">Homely&lt;/a>, I was intrigued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically you own your own components, and pay a monthly fee for monitoring. The components
are mostly &lt;code>Zigbee&lt;/code>-based, and there&amp;rsquo;s a home assistant integration to get the status into my
home assistant setup, so I decided to give it a go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fixing Annoying Flashing With YouTube When Using an AppleTV With LG OLED TV</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-30-fixing-annoying-flashing-with-youtube-when-using-an-appletv-with-lg-oled-tv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-30-fixing-annoying-flashing-with-youtube-when-using-an-appletv-with-lg-oled-tv/</guid><description>&lt;p>So for the longest time I&amp;rsquo;ve been annoyed with black flashing whenever I&amp;rsquo;m watching YouTube videos or shorts on
my AppleTV. I assumed this was related to the black screen between videos, but it turned out this assumption is
wrong! I had set the default output to 4K Dolby Vision, and to adjust to content, but that&amp;rsquo;s sub-optimal. There
is no need to run all your menus and such in Dolby Vision. Instead, set AppleTV to use 4K SDR, and it will
automatically turn on Dolby Vision whenever your content supports it. TIL.
(&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LGOLED/comments/w81fwg/tv_on_then_black_screen_then_picture_pops_back_up/">Source&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Promexplorer</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-19-promexplorer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-19-promexplorer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introducing-promexplorer-a-tool-for-prometheus-metrics-navigation">Introducing Promexplorer: A Tool for Prometheus Metrics Navigation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As software developers, we&amp;rsquo;re constantly inundated with an immense quantity of data and metrics. The influx of
information can sometimes be overwhelming, particularly when you need to sift through a multitude of metrics and
labels. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely why I developed &lt;strong>Promexplorer&lt;/strong> — a tool designed to simplify your interaction with
Prometheus exporter feeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="simplifying-prometheus-metrics">Simplifying Prometheus Metrics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prometheus is a staple in the open-source community, recognized for its robust metrics collection and alerting system.
It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful tool, but navigating some of the larger exporters can sometimes feel like traversing an intricate labyrinth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manage Hugo With Devenv</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-18-manage-hugo-with-devenv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-05-18-manage-hugo-with-devenv/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://devenv.sh">&lt;code>Devenv&lt;/code>&lt;/a> is a nice tool for maintaining your dev environments, spinning up servers, adding
&lt;code>pre-commit&lt;/code>-commit hooks and so on. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a bit for maintaining my
&lt;a href="https://github.com/marcusramberg/nix-config">&lt;code>nix-config&lt;/code>&lt;/a>, as well as some work projects, so while reviving my blog from
it&amp;rsquo;s slumber, I figured I could use it to improve my setup a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Devenv&lt;/code> uses &lt;code>direnv&lt;/code> to install required packages when you enter the project, so we can as least use it to install
&lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code>. Also, a spell checking dictionary could be handy?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conference report FOSDEM 2023</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-02-07-fosdem-2023-conference-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 14:54:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2023-02-07-fosdem-2023-conference-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was really happy to be back in Brussels finally, after some cancelled years due to Covid.
The official beer event at Delirium was still cancelled, but a bunch of us still
gathered there on Friday afternoon. Was great to see old friends from the Open Source
community, but I still managed to get to the ULB on Saturday morning in time for my first talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="saturday">Saturday&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="drawing-k8s-the-right-way">Drawing k8s the right way&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Not a mind blowing beginning, but some nice suggestions for diagramming Kubernetes clusters,
like shaded boxes/color usage, creating things as zones rather than graphs with lines,
and to be sparing with the official icon set, as they are very sharp. Also a good suggestion,
split up a complicated drawing into two simpler ones.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>