<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>design on marcus.means.no</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in design on marcus.means.no</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 23:03:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Draft</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-06-27-draft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 23:03:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-06-27-draft/</guid><description>Generate High Level Cloud Architecture diagrams using YAML syntax - Def need to test this out at work for generating documentation.</description></item><item><title>Makers</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-05-07-makers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-05-07-makers/</guid><description>You can start making something in seconds.
One simple idea is all you need before your brain
automatically explores problems, solutions, and dreams.
Turning that idea into something tangible and wonderful is harder.
You need structure, strategies, people, hard work.
The software world is young and we are still figuring out the most basic processes of the craft. For instance, we tend to label ourself architects or designers, inspired by people who build houses or work in mass production.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-11-01-3127/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-11-01-3127/</guid><description>Jim Wesson aka @hotdogsladies aka Merlin Mann is the customer from hell:
First, and most important, can we do something to make the logo BIGGER and more prominent? I’ve done a quick sketch using the circumference of my coffee cup as a reference guide (see attached) and I’m sure we all agree that the new eagle is much easier to see at about three times the current size (I’m not sure what that is in computer picas).</description></item><item><title>Masters of the hipster-universe</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-09-28-masters-of-the-hipster-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-09-28-masters-of-the-hipster-universe/</guid><description>Awesome hipster He-Man and friends drawings. Must see.</description></item><item><title>Awesome rubber band gun</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-03-24-awesome-rubber-band-gun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-03-24-awesome-rubber-band-gun/</guid><description>By Andy Mangold. Daddy, please make me one like that. And get me a pony while you're at it?</description></item><item><title>Facebook vanity URLs</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-03-22-facebook-vanity-urls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-03-22-facebook-vanity-urls/</guid><description>Chris has a interesting analysis of a recent move by Facebook to support username urls:
Arrington has a post that claims that "Facebook is getting wise to something MySpace has known from the start - users love vanity URLs."
I don’t buy it. In fact, I’m pretty sure that the omission of vanity URLs on Facebook is an intentional design decision from the beginning, and one that I’ve learned to appreciate over time.</description></item><item><title>Why your avatar matters</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-02-05-why-your-avatar-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-02-05-why-your-avatar-matters/</guid><description>Good article about Avatars. As we continue to build our internet personalities, branding gets more and more important. Wonder if I should add an avatar to the sidebar of this blog?
I tend to switch between a Self portrait I took while Photographing ABC Startsiden and my Manga me (From Face your manga). I feel that both of them work, as the manga one is quite recognizable), but I would love to get a good hand-drawn one, as I feel the manga ones are a bit generic.</description></item></channel></rss>