<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on marcus</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/blogs/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on marcus</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:37:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing ... Me</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-09-29-introducing-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-09-29-introducing-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>
 Hey there, the internet is a turbulent place, and since I&amp;#8217;ve moved
 around quite a few times, I think I forgot to introduce myself the last time I
 made the move. I am Marcus Ramberg, the writer of this blog, and director of
 Nordaaker, a small British/Norwegian company currently run out of Oslo,
 Norway. In addition to being my personal blog, at the time being this blog
 acts as Nordaaker&amp;#8217;s dynamic english presence. As the other director of
 Nordaaker, Arne Fismen runs our
 &lt;a href="http://arne.nordaaker.com/">norwegian presence&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We Are Iron Man</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-04-22-we-are-iron-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-04-22-we-are-iron-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>
 Went to visit the Oslo rubyists today just to get the old worn out 'But we
 heard perl is dead', as a welcome. So worn out. Somehow they acknowledge that
 python is a nice language tho. So why has nobody heard from us in a while?
 Matt has a theory.
&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
 &lt;p>
 But here's my point: Perl people hang out on mailing lists. We bottom post,
 carefully interleaved, with 76 character lines. We have signatures that meet
 the McQ standard for acceptable size. We hang out on IRC servers and bitch,
 moan, interact and collaborate with the aid of an 80x25 xterm with irssi,
 BitchX or IrcII in it[3]. Sometimes we sit at home with a beer and do one or
 more of the above. Forums? Meh. Those are the things the PHPtards like
 because they can't figure out how to work a mailing list, right? Blogs?
 That's not even a fucking word! I mean, in my day, we posted to usenet using
 Larry Wall's rn that didn't even have decent fucking threading, and we
 schlepped the posts about from one bnews spool to another over 1200 baud
 dial-up links, and we liked it!
 &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>