<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Untagged on Suburban Nerd</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/untagged/</link><description>Recent content in Untagged on Suburban Nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gitorious now powered by norwegian company</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-12-gitorious-now-powered-by-norwegian-company/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-12-gitorious-now-powered-by-norwegian-company/</guid><description>Even though we're currently using github for all our git hosting needs, we do like the open source alternative gitorious. It makes us happy that it's now officially supported by some of our favorite rubyists from Oslo.
Gitorious now is a project maintained by Shortcut AS, which I co-founded. Shortcut AS now officially supports and develops Gitorious in cooperation with contributors outside Shortcut. Gitorious is, and will continue to be, 100% free software, licensed under the Affero GPL.</description></item><item><title>Last Ninja on the WII</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-last-ninja-on-the-wii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-last-ninja-on-the-wii/</guid><description>Nintendo has started offering C64 titles on the WII, and one of the launch titles are one of my all time favorite games, The Last Ninja. I just spent way too much time getting through that swamp. If you don't know what it's all about, you can check out this long play video.
Another launch title is International Karate, which was arguably my first exposure to Versus Fighting Games, a category that have consumed more of my time than any others, with game series like Street Fighter and Tekken.</description></item></channel></rss>