<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Suburban Nerd</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Suburban Nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 08:28:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View from train office</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-15-view-from-train-office/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 08:28:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-15-view-from-train-office/</guid><description/></item><item><title>My weekend project</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/my-weekend-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/my-weekend-project/</guid><description>Really wanted a nice outdoor sofa for our terrace, and this one looks great. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to cut and sand all the wood and make the first frame. Hoping to complete it next weekend.
Note, I did find a bug in these drawings. Arms need to be 29.5&amp;rdquo;, not 28.5&amp;rdquo; as 28.5-2-2 is 24.5 not 25.5 :-/</description></item><item><title>Coturn for WebRTC NAT Traversal</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/coturn-for-webrtc-nat-traversal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/coturn-for-webrtc-nat-traversal/</guid><description>This article will show you how to set up Coturn. This is a service that allows hosts behind NAT to communicate peer to peer with webrtc. STUN is helping to negotiate port/ip and TURN will proxy the actual traffic if all else fails.
We&amp;rsquo;re using this with Convos&amp;rsquo; video IRC feature, but the same applies to other WebRTC projects.
Installation I&amp;rsquo;ll be assuming you&amp;rsquo;re on Ubutunu for this tutorial, so users on other distros will have to adjust the setup for their environment.</description></item><item><title>Graabein redux</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-graabein-redux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 21:00:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-graabein-redux/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bbq</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-bbq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 18:30:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-bbq/</guid><description/></item><item><title>First GIF</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-first-gif/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:38:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-12-first-gif/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Posting to Hugo from iOS</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/posting-to-hugo-from-ios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/posting-to-hugo-from-ios/</guid><description>I like to take pictures, and some of the point for me of rebooting this blog was to have a place I control myself to publish things, rather than relying on Facebook or Instagram to own my data. However, since my trusty iPhone is my camera 99% of the time, that means I rely on having a simple way to post from the phone, otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s just not going to happen.</description></item><item><title>Oslo Sunset</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-11-oslo-sunset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 12:08:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-11-oslo-sunset/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Post to Hugo from ios with Editorial and Working Copy</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick workflow to post to a Hugo blog on the go using Editorial and Working Copy.</description></item><item><title>Graabein</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-09-graabein/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 19:53:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-09-graabein/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How Cloudflare is using Nomad</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/how-cloudflare-is-using-nomad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/how-cloudflare-is-using-nomad/</guid><description>Hashicorp has made some of my favorite tools for cloud architecture, including Terraform, Consul and Vault. One interesting component I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to try is Nomad; a lightweight alternative to Kubernetes for keeping your container workload running.
Cool to see how Cloudflare is using it.</description></item><item><title>beorg - org mode on the go</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</guid><description>One of the big reasons I finally succumbed to the Evil side was the search for a comprehensive notes and todo system.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing many approaches, like Taskwarrior and Workflowy, but org-mode is by far the best I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far.
In 2020 mobile is a critical component for such a system, and thus beorg was an important part of that decision. It&amp;rsquo;s an impressive piece of software, implementing all the important features of org mode like syncing, all aspects of sheduling and repeats , custom todo states and a comprehensive parser.</description></item><item><title>Visual Fill Column Mode</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/visual-fill-column-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/visual-fill-column-mode/</guid><description>When writing text content, soft wrap is preferable to breaking lines. However, with emacs soft wrap defaults to the line of your window, which could be quite long. This ELPA module allows you to configure the line length to your preference.
*</description></item><item><title>Blog reboot</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-06-blog-reboot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-06-blog-reboot/</guid><description>Blogging in general seems like it has taken a hit, and this blog is no exception. However, I would like to do my part to keep the Indie-web alive, and the first part of contributing is to actually write things, so I figure I might as well try to reboot this blog.
Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten way into org mode and doom emacs, so it felt pretty natural to use that as my vehicle for returning to blogging.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from building a 270 racing quad</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-10-31-lessons-from-building-a-270-racing-quad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-10-31-lessons-from-building-a-270-racing-quad/</guid><description>After buying A little toy quad copter this summer, I got very interested in RC flying. My wife would probably say obsessed. :) In particular I&amp;rsquo;m interested in First Person View racing.
This is a hobby where you crash a lot, so I decided to build it from scratch so I would be able to service it. Turns out it is a lot of work! Yesterday I finally reached my goal of flying FPV, and it was glorious.</description></item><item><title>Too much scifi not enough MCs</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-09-30-too-much-scifi-not-enough-mcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-09-30-too-much-scifi-not-enough-mcs/</guid><description>Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s the end of the month, and I did not manage to keep my promise to myself, and write my blog posts earlier than last month. So, in order to not lose my bet with @jhthorsen, I will tell you about the last four books I finished. It just so happens they are all scifi, and they are all set in the near future, even if their themes are quite different.</description></item><item><title>Porting AnsibleModule to Perl.</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-08-31-porting-ansiblemodule-to-perl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-08-31-porting-ansiblemodule-to-perl/</guid><description>“All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.” ― George Orwell, Animal Farm Ansible is a great orchestration tool, which I&amp;rsquo;ve used extensively for the last years to build infrastructure, or even to accomplish routine tasks like restarting a group of web servers one by one or patching a bunch of servers for critical security issues.
Ansible is written in Python, but you can write modules in anything that can generate JSON.</description></item><item><title>offline decentralized single sign-on in the browser</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-15-desentralized-passwordless-browser-auth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-15-desentralized-passwordless-browser-auth/</guid><description>Recently, browsers have just begun to implement web cryptography. This means that browsers are now capable of the same kind of passwordless decentralized authentication schemes we&amp;rsquo;ve had server-side with ssh and tls asymmetric keys for decades.
I think this is super interesting. I wonder if users are going to be able to understand how to use it tho. I do want to try.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the Thinkpad Buttonless Touchpad</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-07-thinkpad-touchpad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-07-thinkpad-touchpad/</guid><description>The default configuration of the xf86-input-synaptics driver makes the clickpad almost unusable (on the T440s). Clicks/Taps do not register properly, misclicking, no palm detection, no soft buttons where they should be, and so on&amp;hellip; The following configuration can be put in /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d/99-synaptics.conf As a result the clickpad will react a lot more &amp;lsquo;calm&amp;rsquo; than before and the middle &amp;amp; right click button areas match with the printed ones on top of the clickpad.</description></item><item><title>How GitHub uses GitHub to document GitHub</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-github-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-github-documentation/</guid><description>Documentation teams across GitHub can take advantage of the GitHub Flow, Jekyll 2.0, and GitHub Pages to produce high-quality documentation. The benefits that GitHub Pages provides to our Documentation team is already available to any user running a GitHub Pages site.
Great dogfooding</description></item></channel></rss>