<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Suburban Nerd</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Suburban Nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog reboot</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-06-blog-reboot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2020-06-06-blog-reboot/</guid><description>Blogging in general seems like it has taken a hit, and this blog is no exception. However, I would like to do my part to keep the Indie-web alive, and the first part of contributing is to actually write things, so I figure I might as well try to reboot this blog.
Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten way into org mode and doom emacs, so it felt pretty natural to use that as my vehicle for returning to blogging.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from building a 270 racing quad</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-10-31-lessons-from-building-a-270-racing-quad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-10-31-lessons-from-building-a-270-racing-quad/</guid><description>After buying A little toy quad copter this summer, I got very interested in RC flying. My wife would probably say obsessed. :) In particular I&amp;rsquo;m interested in First Person View racing.
This is a hobby where you crash a lot, so I decided to build it from scratch so I would be able to service it. Turns out it is a lot of work! Yesterday I finally reached my goal of flying FPV, and it was glorious.</description></item><item><title>Too much scifi not enough MCs</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-09-30-too-much-scifi-not-enough-mcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-09-30-too-much-scifi-not-enough-mcs/</guid><description>Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s the end of the month, and I did not manage to keep my promise to myself, and write my blog posts earlier than last month. So, in order to not lose my bet with @jhthorsen, I will tell you about the last four books I finished. It just so happens they are all scifi, and they are all set in the near future, even if their themes are quite different.</description></item><item><title>Porting AnsibleModule to Perl.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-08-31-porting-ansiblemodule-to-perl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-08-31-porting-ansiblemodule-to-perl/</guid><description>“All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.” ― George Orwell, Animal Farm Ansible is a great orchestration tool, which I&amp;rsquo;ve used extensively for the last years to build infrastructure, or even to accomplish routine tasks like restarting a group of web servers one by one or patching a bunch of servers for critical security issues.
Ansible is written in Python, but you can write modules in anything that can generate JSON.</description></item><item><title>offline decentralized single sign-on in the browser</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-15-desentralized-passwordless-browser-auth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-15-desentralized-passwordless-browser-auth/</guid><description>Recently, browsers have just begun to implement web cryptography. This means that browsers are now capable of the same kind of passwordless decentralized authentication schemes we&amp;rsquo;ve had server-side with ssh and tls asymmetric keys for decades.
I think this is super interesting. I wonder if users are going to be able to understand how to use it tho. I do want to try.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the Thinkpad Buttonless Touchpad</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-07-thinkpad-touchpad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-07-thinkpad-touchpad/</guid><description>The default configuration of the xf86-input-synaptics driver makes the clickpad almost unusable (on the T440s). Clicks/Taps do not register properly, misclicking, no palm detection, no soft buttons where they should be, and so on&amp;hellip; The following configuration can be put in /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d/99-synaptics.conf As a result the clickpad will react a lot more &amp;lsquo;calm&amp;rsquo; than before and the middle &amp;amp; right click button areas match with the printed ones on top of the clickpad.</description></item><item><title>How GitHub uses GitHub to document GitHub</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-github-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-github-documentation/</guid><description>Documentation teams across GitHub can take advantage of the GitHub Flow, Jekyll 2.0, and GitHub Pages to produce high-quality documentation. The benefits that GitHub Pages provides to our Documentation team is already available to any user running a GitHub Pages site.
Great dogfooding</description></item><item><title>NoOps is an awful word</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</guid><description>What do IT Ops do? We manage IT risk on behalf of the business. Thinking Ops is about servers is like thinking Dev is about code cutting.
If you think devops means eliminating operations, you don&amp;rsquo;t understand development or operations.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</guid><description>This post is a quick test to see if I can easily post to my blog from Working Copy and Textastic. It is still a little beta, but it seems very promising!</description></item><item><title>Building Ansible Modules with Perl and Mojolicious</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-10-05-building-ansible-modules-with-perl-and-mojolicious/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-10-05-building-ansible-modules-with-perl-and-mojolicious/</guid><description>While setting up Output, we decided to automate all our infrastructure using Ansible. This lets us easily do zero downtime releases and create new workers as needed to scale. We&amp;rsquo;ve got roles for haproxy, postgresql, nginx, our app servers and a lot more. One thing we&amp;rsquo;ve been handling manually so far is DNS. We&amp;rsquo;re happy Cloudflare users, and they have one of the best DNS admin tools I&amp;rsquo;ve used, but still I felt like we could do better.</description></item><item><title>Convos 0.8 - Spit and polish</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-09-01-convos-0.8-spit-and-polish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-09-01-convos-0.8-spit-and-polish/</guid><description>This fall we released Convos 0.8, with the latest update 0.83 hitting CPAN today. As we&amp;rsquo;re inching closer to 1.0, we&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on polishing the user interface, fixing bugs and other rough patches in the user experience. One of the most important improvements in this round is how you switch between conversations.
Previously, when you pressed shift+enter, we shifted focus to the conversation list on the top, to let you tab through your most recent conversations .</description></item><item><title>Mojolicious::Plugin::RenderSteps</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-27-mojoliciouspluginrendersteps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-27-mojoliciouspluginrendersteps/</guid><description>This weekend I attended the MojoConf hackathon, which was great fun. I had some interesting talks with the rest of the core team, and I collaborated with Joel Berger on Mojo::PG, an adaptor for the Mojo::IOLoop for Postgres. Joel is almost done with a Pool implementation as well, and we&amp;rsquo;ll probably be on CPAN sometime this week.
I also wrote a simple plugin-helper, which I think greatly simplify working with async controllers in Mojolicious.</description></item><item><title>Improved init.d script for unicorn</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-15-better-init.d-script-for-unicorn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-15-better-init.d-script-for-unicorn/</guid><description>I went looking for a init.d script for Unicorn today, and Google seemed to give me various links to this one - It&amp;rsquo;s a nice and simple script, but it has a couple of issues. For one, it&amp;rsquo;s missing the LSB header, and more importantly it is missing status.
This does not make Ansible very happy, as it is using the status to check if the service is running before enforcing state=stopped or state=running.</description></item><item><title>Monit notifications in slack</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-15-monit-notifications-in-slack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-15-monit-notifications-in-slack/</guid><description>A quick ruby script that lets you receive monit notifications in Slack when a process is in trouble on your server.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-12-prose.io/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-12-prose.io/</guid><description>I still prefer to edit my posts in the command line with vim, but prose.io seems like a really nice alternative for when you need to post to Jekyll on the go, from a web browser.</description></item><item><title>Syncthing</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-12-syncthing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-12-syncthing/</guid><description>Syncthing is an Open Source Dropbox/btsync replacement. Been looking for something like this for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Continous Delivery with Drone and Dokku</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-10-continous-delivery-with-drone-and-dokku/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-10-continous-delivery-with-drone-and-dokku/</guid><description>A part of my job as CTO of Output is managing our deployment and production systems. To this end, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time working with virtualization, Docker and automation recently. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share some of our experiences here in the months to come. One of our biggest challenges has been to get a good testing culture internally. To that end, I wanted a solid solution for CI.</description></item><item><title>Mojoconf 2014</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-09-mojoconf-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-09-mojoconf-2014/</guid><description>In just a couple of weeks, we are arranging a new conference in Oslo - Mojoconf - A conference dedicated to the Mojolicious Web Framework, the real time web and Perl. It is a three day affair, with commercial training on friday, talks on saturday, and a hackthon on sunday.
Attending the conference and the hackathon is just 20EUR, and Oslo in the spring time is not bad either, so obey the Hypnotoad and come to Oslo the weekend 23-25 may!</description></item><item><title>Switched to Jekyll</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-08-switched-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-08-switched-to-jekyll/</guid><description>This blog has been dead for a while, and as I pondered why, I realized one thing:
I hate having to log in and write content in the wordpress web app.
To remedy that, I&amp;rsquo;ve switched from Wordpress to Jekyll. Writing markdown straight into vim seems much more likely to happen than posting in the wordpress web editor. In case you are wondering, the theme I&amp;rsquo;m using here is lanyon.</description></item><item><title>vim plugin for jekyll</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-08-vim-plugin-for-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2014-05-08-vim-plugin-for-jekyll/</guid><description>Just added this vim plugin to my vimrc, to make it easy to start a new post. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you could check out the rest of my dotfiles too, if you have suggestions for improvements, create an issue, or at me on Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Perl needs modern garbage collection</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-09-13-perl-needs-modern-garbage-collection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-09-13-perl-needs-modern-garbage-collection/</guid><description>Chromatic just wrote a list of important features that Perl 5 needs. While I agree with most of the listed ones (and in fact contributed to the new p5-mop proposal during the recent Hackathon), I found one feature curiously missing.
I mean, JWZ pointed this out in 1998; Perl garbage collection is a bad joke. That was 14 years ago, and the situation is the same. It is trivial to create a circular reference and trip it up.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Moose Hackathon 2012</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-09-01-moving-to-moose-hackathon-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-09-01-moving-to-moose-hackathon-2013/</guid><description>This week, my excellent Perl Mongers group Oslo.pm, led by the excellent Salve, has arranged an event we called the Moving to Moose Hackathon 2012. The purpose of this event was to promote the adoption of a MOP (Meta Object Protocol) in Perl development. To this effect, we had two groups, the Perl RDF community, looking to adopt moose in their modules, and Stevan Little and his merry gang of p5-mop developers, looking to create a proposal for a MOP in the Perl core itself, to replace the venerable blessed hash object model.</description></item><item><title>Debugging LWP with mitmproxy</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-12-debugging-lwp-with-mitmproxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-12-debugging-lwp-with-mitmproxy/</guid><description>Are you using an LWP app, and trying to debug it? My personal preferences is using mitmproxy.
To get LWP to use mitmproxy, set the following ENV variables:
PERL_LWP_ENV_PROXY=1 HTTPS_PROXY='http://localhost:8080/' ./script/myapp
Note, this also works for apps using Mojo::UserAgent, except you don't need the first ENV variable.</description></item><item><title>Don't animate scrollTo of the body on iOS.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</guid><description>Animate body.offsetTop and body.offsetLeft works great on the desktop, but is hugely buggy on MobileSafari. Instead, make a viewport div that fills the screen, and animate the offset on that.
I hope this helps someone, as I spent 3 hours figuring it out.</description></item><item><title>Makers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-05-07-makers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-05-07-makers/</guid><description>You can start making something in seconds.
One simple idea is all you need before your brain
automatically explores problems, solutions, and dreams.
Turning that idea into something tangible and wonderful is harder.
You need structure, strategies, people, hard work.
The software world is young and we are still figuring out the most basic processes of the craft. For instance, we tend to label ourself architects or designers, inspired by people who build houses or work in mass production.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-05-01-3657/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-05-01-3657/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Onion browser - TOR on IOS</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</guid><description>The Onion Router is a internet project that aims to anonymize your traffic by routing it through a darknet with various exit points to the Internet. Normally you would have to install a browser proxy on your machine to access TOR, but now there's a browser available for the iPad and iPhone.
Of course, I had to test it by checking out the Silk Road, a much publicized "Amazon of illegal drugs"</description></item><item><title>Great Tmux config.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-03-19-great-tmux-config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-03-19-great-tmux-config/</guid><description>I`ve been working a bit on the iPad using Prompt, tmux and vim with a bluetooth keyboard, and this .tmux.conf is essential for efficient work.
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;</description></item><item><title>New Oslo Skyline &amp; Opera</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-03-19-new-oslo-skyline-opera/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-03-19-new-oslo-skyline-opera/</guid><description>&amp;nbsp;</description></item><item><title>A Mojolicious 2011.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-31-a-mojolicious-2011/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-31-a-mojolicious-2011/</guid><description>A new year is upon us, and I figured this would be good time to take a look at the improvements in the Mojolicious framework in the last year. There has been a dazzling number of releases, 122 in fact, including the current release, 2.42.
Some of the releases were mere bugfix releases, with nothing noteworthy to add, but I&amp;#8217;ll try going through the major releases in the last year. When this year started, we already had a robust MVC Web framework, and through the year you will note that a lot of the work has gone into building a first class real time web framework.</description></item><item><title>Beautiful Open Source</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-10-beautiful-open-source/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-10-beautiful-open-source/</guid><description>Earlier today, HP announced that they are open sourcing webOS, the mobile OS that they bought from Palm, inspired by BeOS, which Palm acquired a few years before that. Of course, these news comes as a consequence of HP canning their hardware platform, ending their tablet ambitions in a spectacular fire sale where they lost money on every device sold.
I've been a fan of the simplicity and elegance of webOS for a while.</description></item><item><title>Visualization of the Mojo class tree.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-04-visualization-of-the-mojo-class-tree/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-12-04-visualization-of-the-mojo-class-tree/</guid><description>In this visualization, I've tried to group the various Mojo classes by function and color code them. The classes are placed in layers, and related groups are close to each other. Note that I've dropped abstract base classes and Mojolicious related subclasses from this visualization, as well as some servers and all the commands. This might be useful as a quick reference, if you want to print it, you can get the PDF here.</description></item><item><title>$ mojo get is X-ray for the web</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-11-30-mojo-get-is-x-ray-for-the-web/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-11-30-mojo-get-is-x-ray-for-the-web/</guid><description>Mojolicious isn't just useful for perl coders, it also includes a command line tool that can be quite handy for anybody who wants to get info from the web:
usage: /Users/marcus/perl5/perlbrew/perls/perl-5.14.2/bin/mojo get [OPTIONS] \ URL [SELECTOR] [COMMANDS] mojo get / mojo get mojolicio.us mojo get -v -r google.com mojo get --method POST --content 'trololo' mojolicio.us mojo get --header 'X-Bender: Bite my shiny metal ass!' mojolicio.us mojo get mojolicio.us 'head &amp;gt; title' text mojo get mojolicio.</description></item><item><title>Easily integrating your Mojolicious app with Facebook.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-01-08-easily-integrating-your-mojolicious-app-with-facebook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-01-08-easily-integrating-your-mojolicious-app-with-facebook/</guid><description>Facebook has recently released anew Graph API. It's a simple RESTish API, and uses the newly released OAuth2 spec for authorization. This makes it a great match for Mojolicious, and using my new OAuth2 plugin (Also coming to a CPAN mirror near you), it's absolutely trivial.
Here is a simple Lite example. Just register an app with facebook to get the key and secret.
use Mojolicious::Lite; # configure the plugin plugin 'oauth2', facebook = { key = 'my-key', secret = 'my-secret' }; get 'hello' = sub { My $self=shift; #redirects the gets the token asynchronous $self-get_token('facebook', callback = sub { my $token=shift; my $me=$self-client-get( 'https://graph.</description></item><item><title>iPad as a writer' s tool</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-01-01-ipad-as-a-writer-s-tool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2011-01-01-ipad-as-a-writer-s-tool/</guid><description>I believe I have found my ideal writing tool. For the last couple of months, I have been drafting text using iA Writer on the iPad. While the softward keyboard is cumbersome to use, I find the focus the combination gives very inspiring. Nothing but me and the text, no IMs or emails to disturb me. I have turned off notifications on the iPad, so not even a ongoing game of Words With Friends can spoil my productivity.</description></item><item><title>My first Mojolicious Plugin - Proxy</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-12-16-my-first-mojolicious-plugin-proxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-12-16-my-first-mojolicious-plugin-proxy/</guid><description>A few days ago I uploaded my first Mojolicious plugin to CPAN,Mojolicious::Plugin::Proxy. My use case was that I am writing a simple single-file html5/javascript app, which needed to access a remote JSON feed. When running on a device with file:/// URLs, cross-site scripting is not an issue, but when running on a web-server, my appis unable to reach that remote JSON feed, so I wrote this plugin to allow me to simply proxy JSON requests from the local server to the remote one.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla Javascript documentation</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-09-28-mozilla-javascript-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-09-28-mozilla-javascript-documentation/</guid><description>﻿</description></item><item><title>3 reasons for the lack of updates here lately</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</guid><description>Dark Nebula Episode 2 Gravity Hook Van Helsing</description></item><item><title>i use this, now 50% more social.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-22-i-use-this-now-with-50-more-social/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-22-i-use-this-now-with-50-more-social/</guid><description>We've just pushed a major update to iusethis, adding several social features and updating the commenting system with support for replies. To improve performance, we've also added a new caching system, to allow us to cache more data for logged-in users.
Find your friends Looking up your contacts in GMail is a feature that we've wanted for a long time, but we did not want to compromise users by asking for their passwords.</description></item><item><title>Pure CSS Fail Whale</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-pure-css-fail-whale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-pure-css-fail-whale/</guid><description>Really impressive. When will we see pure CSS animated ads start appearing?</description></item><item><title>The Rules of a Gentleman</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-the-rules-of-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-the-rules-of-a-gentleman/</guid><description>Some of these are obsolete, in my opinion (who wears a watch these days?) But others are really profound. Worth adding to your RSS reader.</description></item><item><title>Turn your iPad into a mifi</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-turn-your-ipad-into-a-mifi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-17-turn-your-ipad-into-a-mifi/</guid><description>Note: I do not recommend doing this. There are easier ways. But still, an awesome hack.</description></item><item><title>Mooseish DBIC Schemas</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-03-mooseish-dbic-schemas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-03-mooseish-dbic-schemas/</guid><description>Longing for a more Mooseish DBIx::Class? Eventually there will be MooseX::DBIC, but if you need something while you're waiting, you could check out MooseX::DBIC::AddColumn which lets you do Moose-like column definitions in your Result classes.</description></item><item><title>Mojolicious GSOC blog</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-02-mojolicious-gsoc-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-02-mojolicious-gsoc-blog/</guid><description>I'm mentoring a Google Summer of Code project to improve the Mojolicious test suite this year, and my student has just set up a blog to journal his progress. Check it out, you might even learn something.</description></item><item><title>DBIx-Class about to switch to git</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-01-dbix-class-about-to-switch-to-git/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-06-01-dbix-class-about-to-switch-to-git/</guid><description>12:27 &amp;lt;ribasushi&amp;gt; a call to all git-heads
12:28 &amp;lt;ribasushi&amp;gt; recently haarg did a seemingly perfect conversion of dbic from svn to git (a non-trivial feat)
12:28 &amp;lt;ribasushi&amp;gt; I am calling for people who actually know git to randomly poke at the new history and notufy me of whatever problems they see
12:28 &amp;lt;ribasushi&amp;gt; http://github.com/haarg/DBIx-Class
12:29 &amp;lt;ribasushi&amp;gt; (also you can ascertain the quality of the conversion, and potentially draft haarg to do a catalyst conversion as well - it took him a couple of freaking hours to do dbic)</description></item><item><title>Github adds inline commit notes.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-github-adds-inline-commit-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-github-adds-inline-commit-notes/</guid><description>Github is probably much of the reason we love using git at Nordaaker. The great overview and administration system, as well as the simple no-nonsense issue tracker works very efficiently for us. Now github has added another feature that I think will help us collaborating efficiently on code.
Inline commit notes lets you comment anywhere in a commit, lending itself to quick code reviews and clarifications.</description></item><item><title>Guess which cartoon hero the ipad won't save?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-guess-which-cartoon-hero-the-ipad-wont-save/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-guess-which-cartoon-hero-the-ipad-wont-save/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to build a offine HTML5 iphone app</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</guid><description>I need to look into this for the iusethis iPhone application. The launch time is one thing that annoys me with that app now, and this could be a good way to sort that out.</description></item><item><title>Last chance to submit a talk for NPW 2010</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-last-chance-to-submit-a-talk-for-npw-2010/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-last-chance-to-submit-a-talk-for-npw-2010/</guid><description>Thinking about submitting a talk for NPW 2010 in Reykjavik? The deadline for the Call for Paper is tomorrow, 29th of march, so you'd better hurry up and get that submission in there. I've submitted a talk, and am really looking forward to visit iceland. I've never been, but from the photos I've seen it seems like a beautyful place.</description></item><item><title>MojaMoja</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-mojamoja/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-28-mojamoja/</guid><description>Yet another Perl MVC micro-framework with a name that will be confused with my wiki software. From the Author's description:
(PoC)yet another sinatra-ish framework built on CPAN module.
Rather than 'shaggadelic' or 'dance', this one starts the app with 'zigorou'. I can't see it catching on.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 useless professions</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-11-top-10-useless-professions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-11-top-10-useless-professions/</guid><description>Healer Astrologer Homeopath Social Media Expert Politician Search Engine Optimization specialist Patent Lawyer Life Coach Personal Shopper Human Resources Manager Did I miss any important ones? Help out by posting on twitter with the #uselessprofessions tag.</description></item><item><title>Ad blockers hurt the sites you love</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-07-ad-blockers-hurt-the-sites-you-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-07-ad-blockers-hurt-the-sites-you-love/</guid><description>Good point from Ars Technica on ad blockers. This is defintively a problem we have with iusethis.com as well, reducing the total number of ad views reduces our revenue. I much prefer people to use a normal flash blocker. I can understand not wanting cpu consuming ads running in every tab of your browser.</description></item><item><title>Slides from my Mojolicious presentation</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-07-slides-from-my-mojolicious-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-03-07-slides-from-my-mojolicious-presentation/</guid><description>I recently held a introduction to the Mojolicious web framework for Oslo.pm. Here are the slides:
Mojolicious View more presentations from marcusramberg.</description></item><item><title>cpanminus - The new CPAN superstar</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-02-21-cpanminus-the-new-cpan-superstar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-02-21-cpanminus-the-new-cpan-superstar/</guid><description>Like most serious Perl people, CPAN is the main reason I still use Perl after all this time. This huge, wonderful library of Perl code usually helps me avoid reinventing any wheels. On the other hand, the standard CPAN client is one of my most regular hate objects when coding Perl.
It's not that it lacks any features I need, rather the opposite, the damn thing has a million options, and no good defaults.</description></item><item><title>Android app?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-02-04-android-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-02-04-android-app/</guid><description>Nordaaker just got an Android device. &amp;lt;a href="http://arne.nordaaker.com/"&amp;gt;Arne&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is currently fondling a Google Nexus One. Sleek piece of hardware. I've been thinking we should do an Android app. Question number one is which language?
21:11 &amp;lt;@sri&amp;gt; java?
21:11 &amp;lt;@marcus&amp;gt; hmm?
21:11 &amp;lt;@marcus&amp;gt; No, I don't think so
21:11 &amp;lt;@marcus&amp;gt; Scala maybe
21:11 &amp;lt;@sri&amp;gt; mhm, scala seems bearable
21:11 &amp;lt;@marcus&amp;gt; my thoughts precicely
&amp;nbsp;</description></item><item><title>Samsung, please let me redesign the ST1000 OS</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-01-15-samsung-please-let-me-redesign-the-st1000-os/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2010-01-15-samsung-please-let-me-redesign-the-st1000-os/</guid><description>I just bought a new compact camera, a Samsung ST1000 (or CL65 in the US). It's a lovely piece of hardware, a 12 mpixel camera with a 28-135 lens and image stabilization, GPS, Wifi all in a small sleek package. However, it has some issues. Here's my reaction as captured on IRC after trying to use the internet sharing features:
21:13 my camera's firmware was written by idiots. 21:14 samsung-- 21:14 it "</description></item><item><title>Burning the candle at both ends part II</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-28-burning-the-candle-at-both-ends-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-28-burning-the-candle-at-both-ends-part-ii/</guid><description>In addition to recent fatherhood and doing my own startup and taking over the leadership of the Oslo Perl Mongers, I've started a project to get a hacker space set up in Oslo. Actually, this ties in to my Oslo Perl Mongers interests as well, so it's not a completely new project. I got very inspired by @kyrah's talk about metalab.at in Wien at FSCons in Gothenburg a couple of weeks ago.</description></item><item><title>Burning the candle at both ends.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-28-burning-the-candle-at-both-ends/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-28-burning-the-candle-at-both-ends/</guid><description>In addition to recent fatherhood and doing my own startup, I am now the leader of the Oslo Perl Mongers. Look forward to tech talks from Oslo.pm in the months to come. :)</description></item><item><title>Testing JavaScript from Perl</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-06-testing-javascript-from-perl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-06-testing-javascript-from-perl/</guid><description>If you want to write tests for your JavaScript code from Perl, Claes' module Test::JavaScript::More comes in handy. This module works by evaling everything from the use line as JavaScript. Of course, now you're mixing two languages in one file, which is not going to make any of your syntax validators happy. However, loading it like this will please both perl and jslint:
m| /* |; # Comment out JavaScript use Test::JavaScript::More; __END__ = ''; // It's is all JS from here.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-01-3127/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-11-01-3127/</guid><description>Jim Wesson aka @hotdogsladies aka Merlin Mann is the customer from hell:
First, and most important, can we do something to make the logo BIGGER and more prominent? I’ve done a quick sketch using the circumference of my coffee cup as a reference guide (see attached) and I’m sure we all agree that the new eagle is much easier to see at about three times the current size (I’m not sure what that is in computer picas).</description></item><item><title>The fallacy of excuses.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-17-the-fallacy-of-excuses-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-17-the-fallacy-of-excuses-/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Amazon announces same day delivery</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-16-amazon-announces-same-day-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-16-amazon-announces-same-day-delivery/</guid><description>Whoever decides to provide this service in Oslo for a reasonable price will have me as a loyal customer. Amazon is charging 15$ for normal customers and 6$ for prime customers. Would make a prime membership worth it quite quickly if you live in one of those target cities I guess. (via daring fireball).</description></item><item><title>Nordaaker enters show biz ... In Norwegian</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-15-nordaaker-enters-show-biz-in-norwegian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-15-nordaaker-enters-show-biz-in-norwegian/</guid><description>Just a quick note to the Norwegian</description></item><item><title>Creating QR barcodes with perl.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-08-creating-qr-barcodes-with-perl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-08-creating-qr-barcodes-with-perl/</guid><description>A really simple tutorial for creating these 2d-barcodes that you see android use all the time.</description></item><item><title>Things you don't want to see in your server console.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-07-things-you-dont-want-to-see-in-your-server-console/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-10-07-things-you-dont-want-to-see-in-your-server-console/</guid><description> 2190872.796576] Unable to handle kernel NULL pointer dereference [2190872.796765] tsk-{mm,active_mm}-context = 00000000000016ca [2190872.796810] tsk-{mm,active_mm}-pgd = fffff800b6244000 [2190872.796853] \|/ ____ \|/ [2190872.796860] "@'/ .. @" [2190872.796867] /_| \__/ |_\ [2190872.796875] \__U_/ [2190872.797141] swapper(0[#0]): Oops [#1] [2190872.797271] TSTATE: 0000009911001600 TPC: 0000000000000000 TNPC: 0000000000000004 Y: 00000000 Not tainted [2190872.797387] TPC: &amp;lt;0x8</description></item><item><title>Introducing ... Me</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-29-introducing-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-29-introducing-me/</guid><description>Hey there, the internet is a turbulent place, and since I&amp;#8217;ve moved around quite
a few times, I think I forgot to introduce myself the last time I made the
move. I am Marcus Ramberg, the writer of this blog, and director of
Nordaaker, a small British/Norwegian company currently run out of Oslo,
Norway. In addition to being my personal blog, at the time being this blog
acts as Nordaaker&amp;#8217;s dynamic english presence.</description></item><item><title>Masters of the hipster-universe</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-masters-of-the-hipster-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-masters-of-the-hipster-universe/</guid><description>Awesome hipster He-Man and friends drawings. Must see.</description></item><item><title>mirrorshades.net - Excellent operations blog</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-mirroshades-net-excellent-operations-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-mirroshades-net-excellent-operations-blog/</guid><description>If you are interested in system administration and Unix/Solaris/Virtualization, my friend Bryan D. Allen's new work blog mirrorshades.net is a must-add to your feed reader. I'm going to be looking into Puppet Real Soon Now.</description></item><item><title>Tetris Skaters</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-tetris-skaters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-28-tetris-skaters/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Catalyst cares about your old code</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-catalyst-cares-about-your-old-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-catalyst-cares-about-your-old-code/</guid><description>09:52 wow.. you can actually see how old that code is 10:00 but it still runs without a single modification. nice! 10:00 catalyst++ 10:14 rafl: try that with rails :) 10:14 no, thanks Code rot is everywhere, but some platforms suffer more than others. Even Simple C++ code suffers from code rot.</description></item><item><title>iPhone 3GS series from Aker Brygge</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-iphone-3gs-series-from-aker-brygge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-04-iphone-3gs-series-from-aker-brygge/</guid><description>Glass Construction by Marcus Ramberg.
Went for a quick bike ride near Aker Brygge this morning and tested the iPhone 3GS camera. I'd like a tripod mount so I can film from the bike with it. Will test out with the gorillapod and my flip mino hd.
Update: The first set I published was post-processed using adobe lightroom to give them a mood I like. For reference, I've uploaded the non-postprocessed versions as well</description></item><item><title>Catalyst::Plugin::AutoCRUD</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-02-catalystpluginautocrud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-09-02-catalystpluginautocrud/</guid><description>One major factor in Catalyst's success has been extensibility. I plan to
do a series on extensions that I've found useful recently. To kick it off,
I'll feature a model which gives me a simple and useful admin interface to
my DBIx::Class models.
When I first got involved with MVC Web Frameworks like Maypole and Ruby on
Rails, a big selling point was the ability to generate CRUD (Create/Read/
Update/Delete) interfaces to your data model.</description></item><item><title>SD available for general use</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-27-sd-available-for-general-use/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-27-sd-available-for-general-use/</guid><description>Jesse Vincent of RT and Hiveminder fame has just announced that his new system SD is available for public use.
SD (Simple Defects) is a peer-to-peer issue tracking system built on top of Prophet. In addition to being a full-fledged distributed bug tracker, SD can also bidirectionally sync with your RT, Hiveminder, Trac, GitHub or Google Code issue tracker.
You can install SD with the CPAN shell by doing $ cpan App::SD For more info, read the release announcement.</description></item><item><title>Sebastian on MS IIS' FastCGI support.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-11-sebastian-on-ms-iis-fastcgi-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-11-sebastian-on-ms-iis-fastcgi-support/</guid><description> 09:30 there is absolutely no way to detect the server base as far as i can see 09:33 you really have to do horrible things with PATH_TRANSLATED... 09:34 seriously... was that thing developed by a bunch of monkeys? 10:00 yeah, they were trying to write shakespeare's collected works, and ended up with IIS instead</description></item><item><title>Sitting under a tree</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-09-sitting-under-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-09-sitting-under-a-tree/</guid><description>Sitting under a tree by Marcus Ramberg</description></item><item><title>Model adaptors for Catalyst.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-07-model-adaptors-for-catalyst/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-07-model-adaptors-for-catalyst/</guid><description>In a recent post Dave Rolsky points out some of his own best practices for Catalyst. While I've come around to agree with his first point, that Catalyst should generate a reusable config class for the user, I'm not so sure with regards to his model viewpoints.
For me, the strength of Catalyst's Model layer has always been the immense glue layer that allows me to configure any model in a predictable way.</description></item><item><title>Putting your favorite apps on your blog</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-07-putting-your-favorite-apps-on-your-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-07-putting-your-favorite-apps-on-your-blog/</guid><description>In this article I will show you how you can add a sidebar-item with your favorite apps to your favorite blog template.</description></item><item><title>3D with HTML5 Canvas series</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-3d-with-html5-canvas-series/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-3d-with-html5-canvas-series/</guid><description>Mr Speaker is doing a series of posts on how to do 3d graphics with the HTML 5 Canvas:
This introductory post – to set up viewer expectations A 3D starfield – to learn how to project points in 3D 2D shape rotation – gotta rotate stuff, and that seems hard 3D wireframe drawing – draw a cube! Yeah! 3D wireframe rotating &amp; moving – spin it! ‘Shaded’ 3D model – colour it in.</description></item><item><title>Bootylicious - Single file Mojo based blog</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-bootylicious-single-file-mojo-based-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-bootylicious-single-file-mojo-based-blog/</guid><description>As you might know, Sebastian recently added single-file support to his Mojolicious framework. Viacheslav Tikhanovskii has taken this functionality and run with it, producing bootylicious - a ~280 SLOC web log system. It sorts a directory of POD formatted blog posts, and even supports RSS. I think these single file apps is an excellent way to demonstrate your framework. I actually remember this as being a selling point for Maypole back in the days :)</description></item><item><title>Modding kindle for european networks</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-modding-kindle-for-european-networks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-08-06-modding-kindle-for-european-networks/</guid><description>So some European madman got himself a Kindle on the 30. July, and the first thing he did with it is pop it open and replace the US-centric mobile card:
I modded the
Kindle 2 with a
3G HSPA modem and a
Simcard holder for use in
Europe.
Apparently It's not tested at all yet, so I'm very interested to see how this turns out. He will probably need some software support to get it working.</description></item><item><title>Initial Impressions of Catalyst Book | A Foolish Manifesto</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-24-initial-impressions-of-catalyst-book-a-foolish-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-24-initial-impressions-of-catalyst-book-a-foolish-manifesto/</guid><description>Frew Schmidt has read the first four chapter of the new Catalyst book and gives some first impressions:
So far though, I would say that the book is better than most programming books. Really, a lot of programming books need to be more like this, instead of focusing entirely on the arcana of one framework they should help you be a better programmer overall.</description></item><item><title>A great historical look at pobox.com logos</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-10-a-great-historical-look-at-pobox-com-logos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-10-a-great-historical-look-at-pobox-com-logos/</guid><description>Pobox Blog.</description></item><item><title>Pobox Blog: Pobox: In love with logos since 1995!</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-10-pobox-blog-pobox-in-love-with-logos-since-1995-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-10-pobox-blog-pobox-in-love-with-logos-since-1995-/</guid><description>Pobox Blog: Pobox: In love with logos since 1995!.</description></item><item><title>ChromeOS does not a monopoly make.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-chromeos-does-not-a-monopoly-make/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-chromeos-does-not-a-monopoly-make/</guid><description>Chill out people. ChromeOS might be interesting and all, but it's not going to be killing any operating systems in the near future. Chrome has enough of a challenge keeping up with the other browsers, not to mention being able to replace modern desktop operating systems. As usual, Ted Dzuiba has dissected this situation with much more wit than I could muster:
Keep whackin' away on that Pareto Principle and let us all know how it turns out.</description></item><item><title>Tab bar or no Tab bar?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</guid><description>Interesting writeup from Justin Williams about the use of Tab Bars in iPhone development. One of his big gripes is related to the space the tabbar uses:
When I made the decision, my thinking was that the application had four separate features, so it only made sense to separate them using the tab bar. What I found as I got further into the development of the application was that the bottom tab bar was incredibly limiting for where to place extra controls.</description></item><item><title>2008: A year of OSM edits</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-29-2008-a-year-of-osm-edits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-29-2008-a-year-of-osm-edits/</guid><description>Amazing demonstration of the power of the net. OpenStreetMap.org still has some way to go, but I think it's one of the more interesting open projects out there.</description></item><item><title>Your language makes you Think Different.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-29-your-language-makes-you-think-different/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-29-your-language-makes-you-think-different/</guid><description>Lera Boroditsky's findings about how our language decides how we think about things is a captivating read. I think this research supports my notion that we will require a common world language to be able to truly communicate as equals, and to be able to progress as a peaceful species. She comes with many examples on how the differences affect fundamental things in our lives. I did not actually know that Russians think of death as a woman, but it explains a lot :)</description></item><item><title>Senseless install tests considered harmful</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-24-senseless-install-tests-considered-harmful/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-24-senseless-install-tests-considered-harmful/</guid><description>For the past couple of days. I have been working on setting up a second frontend web node for iusethis.com, as well as rebuilding my development environment after upgrading my laptop to snow leopard (XS modules seems to be broken on that environment for now, so I'm developing in a vmware ubuntu image instead).
Most of this time has been spent watching my various systems running test after test of CPAN modules, which has made me realize two things.</description></item><item><title>The magic JFDI environment variable for CPAN</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-24-the-magic-jfdi-environment-variable-for-cpan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-24-the-magic-jfdi-environment-variable-for-cpan/</guid><description>I've been installing a lot of modules lately, and they keep asking a lot of stupid things. However, Caelum finally gave me the solution to shut them up:
17:03 marcus: PERL_MM_USE_DEFAULT=1 17:04 it just stops any prompting</description></item><item><title>Excellent news about Norway</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-20-excellent-news-about-norway/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-20-excellent-news-about-norway/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Screencast: Introduction to Catalyst by Dan Dascalescu</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-20-screencast-introduction-to-catalyst-by-dan-dascalescu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-20-screencast-introduction-to-catalyst-by-dan-dascalescu/</guid><description>Suck on that, RoR :-)</description></item><item><title>TextMate 2: It's coming</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-14-2517/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-14-2517/</guid><description>Allan Odgaard reassures us that TextMate 2 isn't going to be a Duke Nukem Forever:
So where does development stand for 2.0? It feels to me like most of the modules are getting close, say 90%. But as they say, on the horizon, mountains look small.
I guess he just has the remaining 90% to finish. :) I for one think this is exciting news. TextMate is probably my second most used program after Firefox.</description></item><item><title>GitHub:FI pricing now public</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-11-githubfi-pricing-now-public/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-11-githubfi-pricing-now-public/</guid><description>GitHub created a headache for themselves at the initial launch of their inhouse hosting option for companies wanting to use GitHub.
That, coupled with the fact that we wanted companies to sign an NDA before receiving their quote, slowed the entire process down. It also bewildered more than a few people wondering why lawyers needed to be involved just to figure out how much the product cost.
Well, now they are up for everybody to see, but boy, with prices like that, I can see why they would like to keep them secret.</description></item><item><title>Migrating SVN repositories to Git, The Right Way</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-11-migrating-svn-repositories-to-git-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-11-migrating-svn-repositories-to-git-the-right-way/</guid><description>Yuval takes our hand and guides us through the proper process for migrating your SVN repository to Git:
Having an accurate revision control history is very helpful for tracking down regressions. Here's my take on how to do this properly.
Hopefully someone can use this to migrate over Catalyst-Runtime to our spanking new Catalyst git repository.</description></item><item><title>Unfortunately, I am not that lucky :-/</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-10-unfortunately-i-am-not-that-lucky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-10-unfortunately-i-am-not-that-lucky/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quick textmate tip for Perlers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-09-quick-textmate-tip-for-perlers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-09-quick-textmate-tip-for-perlers/</guid><description>Using Textmate for Perl programming? As you probably know, the Perl bundle supports validating your perl syntax with a quick shortcut. However, I picked up a quick tip from the "Javascript Tools" bundle. If you rebind the command as ⌘-S, TextMate will automatically check your syntax every time you save a Perl file. In case you need help doing this:
In the menu Go to Bundles - Bundle Editor - Show Bundle Editor</description></item><item><title>Lullaby</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-05-lullaby/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-05-lullaby/</guid><description>:|: Byssan lull -- boil the full kettle,
the treasure chest has three figures. :|:
The first one is our faith
the second one is hope,
the third one is the red love. -- Evert Taube</description></item><item><title>Voted most likely time waster - Fall 2009</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-04-voted-most-likely-time-waster-fall-2009/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-04-voted-most-likely-time-waster-fall-2009/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using Cruise Control with Perl projects</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-03-using-cruise-control-with-perl-projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-03-using-cruise-control-with-perl-projects/</guid><description>I often</description></item><item><title>Why PHP support in MS Azure is FAIL</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-03-why-php-support-in-ms-azure-is-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-06-03-why-php-support-in-ms-azure-is-fail/</guid><description>I do not hate PHP. Ted Dziuba describes my feelings about it perfectly:
Yes, let me introduce you to the professional PHP programmer. You see, PHP is like a handgun. On its own, it is simply an inanimate tool that has no moral leaning. In the hands of a responsible citizen, it can be used to the benefit of society. But in the hands of someone who is untrained or mentally unstable, it can be used to commit horrible atrocities.</description></item><item><title>I love lazy web / Catalyst dispatcher graphs</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-31-i-love-lazy-web-catalyst-dispatcher-graphs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-31-i-love-lazy-web-catalyst-dispatcher-graphs/</guid><description>So, it seems that people are actually reading my ramblings. For instance, Franck Cuny read my description of the Mojo routes graph generator. Then he took it upon himself to write the Catalyst equivalent. That is just so awesome! Frank says "For the moment only private actions are graphed.", hopefully, it can be extended to understand chained actions. I can't wait to test it out on the iusethis code base. Now I can just hand this graph to Arne when he wants to know which template matches which action.</description></item><item><title>Diary of an app store reviewer</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</guid><description>Gruber has written a brilliant guess at what must be going on inside the heads of the Apple App Store reviewers' mind. I specially enjoyed this nugget:
I could read that over and over. It’s like the voice of a robot. The voice of authority. The voice of authoritative robots.</description></item><item><title>Just in case I'm not the only one who missed this.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-just-in-case-im-not-the-only-one-who-missed-this/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-30-just-in-case-im-not-the-only-one-who-missed-this/</guid><description>Seems DBIx::Class, the greatest Perl object-relational mapper ever, has recently added support for subqueries:
22:04 * marcus looks at DBIC cookbook, realizes it has subquery support now. *head explosion* 22:04 since 081, yes :) Even tho most things can be rewritten as joins, this has been one of the few things I've been missing in this excellent ORM. It's still marked as experimental, but I'm totally going to be using it from now on :) Apparently this is how it works:</description></item><item><title>Awesome route graph with MojoX::Routes::AsGraph</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-awesome-route-graph-with-mojoxroutesasgraph/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-awesome-route-graph-with-mojoxroutesasgraph/</guid><description>We are testing out Sebastian's Mojolicious framework for use in a Nordaaker project. Mojolicious uses an routes-based dispatcher, which is nice, but sometimes it's hard to keep track of how everything is routed. Luckily Melo already has an excellent solution for this:
Just check out MojoX::Routes::AsGraph , which can generate these lovely graphs for you. It can even generate Ascii graphs, if you're a hard-core console user (Thanks to vti for telling me about that, as well as showing me this module in the first place :).</description></item><item><title>Tactical overview of your varnish instances</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-tactical-overview-of-your-varnish-instances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-tactical-overview-of-your-varnish-instances/</guid><description>varnish-top is a handy util for keeping track of our varnish installation (via Denis). From the google-code project page page:
Simply, it is a tool that lets you monitor a few key stats from one or more varnish boxes in real-time, from the command line, in a top-like screen. It's not the most sophisticated tool, but is handy for seeing a real-time view into how your box(es) are doing without needing to set up graphing, open up a browser, etc.</description></item><item><title>The Vendor Client relationship - in real world situations</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-the-vendor-client-relationship-in-real-world-situations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-27-the-vendor-client-relationship-in-real-world-situations/</guid><description>As a small business owner, I have to say... Best video ever.</description></item><item><title>Handy varnish tips</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-25-handy-varnish-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-25-handy-varnish-tips/</guid><description>We depend heavily on the varnish cache to run iusethis and our other sites. These tips from kristian@linpro are a must read:
ESI is cool. And requires more session workspace. If you don’t increase the value of sess_workspace (default: 16kb. Adviced value: 32kb or more), you are likely to see assert errors in your syslog.
(Hint: If you are going wtf is ESI, you really want to find out more :)</description></item><item><title>Baklia Night Sky</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-24-baklia-night-sky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-24-baklia-night-sky/</guid><description>Baklia Night Sky by Marcus Ramberg
Took this before going to bed late last night.</description></item><item><title>An inconvenient trend</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-an-inconvenient-trend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-an-inconvenient-trend/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fixing the POD synopsis in OSX</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-fixing-the-pod-synopsis-in-osx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-fixing-the-pod-synopsis-in-osx/</guid><description>Having problems copying example code from POD and getting invalid characters in your Perl? Apparently this is a problem with nroff on OS X (According to my linux hacking peeps), but the solution is quite simple. Just stuff this in your .profile or whatever ;)
alias perldoc='perldoc -t'
And your pod is rendered in glorious pure-text, without using weird characters for ' and -.</description></item><item><title>Reasons to not use CouchDB</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-reasons-to-not-use-couchdb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-18-reasons-to-not-use-couchdb/</guid><description>It's quite interesting to read nothingmuch' reasons for not using CouchDB. In particular this is a bit of a wakeup call for me:
This means that you have to live with the same limitations of SQL queries (the fact that they are non recursive, so they can't express transitive relationships), but you don't get the freedom to write queries ad hoc and have them execute efficiently (ad hoc views are supported, but there are no general purposes indexes).</description></item><item><title>Even Enterprise thinks enterprise sucks</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-even-enterprise-thinks-enterprise-sucks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-even-enterprise-thinks-enterprise-sucks/</guid><description>Early in my career I worked for a large telco at. The term "Enterprise Software" still gives me me chills down the spine. Likewise terms like WS-* and SOA, which for me represents huge amounts of bloat and hatefulness.
This is in fact one of the reasons I prefer working in smaller more agile shops. Apparently, I'm not alone in disliking enterprise software. Software AG's "Chief Strategist" Miko Matsumura sums it up well:</description></item><item><title>Quicksilver plugin for iusethis.com</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-quicksilver-plugin-for-iusethiscom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-quicksilver-plugin-for-iusethiscom/</guid><description>Quicksilver is one tool I can't live without. When I use a Mac without it, I feel handicapped. I've been doing some iPhone development lately, and I am feel comfortable with Objective-C. Yesterday I decided to write a Quicksilver plugin. This tutorial series made it easy. I have made a video using Snapz Pro to show how it works:
You can download it right now and try it out. Like other utilities we make for iusethis, it's free and open source (Artistic/GPL dual licensed).</description></item><item><title>Selective red</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-selective-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-15-selective-red/</guid><description>Selective red by Marcus Ramberg.</description></item><item><title>The calendar as a filter</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-13-the-calendar-as-a-filter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-13-the-calendar-as-a-filter/</guid><description>http://dilbert.com/blog/entry/calendar_as_filter/</description></item><item><title>Gitorious now powered by norwegian company</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-12-gitorious-now-powered-by-norwegian-company/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-12-gitorious-now-powered-by-norwegian-company/</guid><description>Even though we're currently using github for all our git hosting needs, we do like the open source alternative gitorious. It makes us happy that it's now officially supported by some of our favorite rubyists from Oslo.
Gitorious now is a project maintained by Shortcut AS, which I co-founded. Shortcut AS now officially supports and develops Gitorious in cooperation with contributors outside Shortcut. Gitorious is, and will continue to be, 100% free software, licensed under the Affero GPL.</description></item><item><title>MooseX multi method dispatch is second to none.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-05-moosex-multi-method-dispatch-is-second-to-none/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-05-moosex-multi-method-dispatch-is-second-to-none/</guid><description>You might have an awesome OO system if:
you are able to implement Rock-Paper-Scissors-Lizard-Spock using nothing but multi methods (via nothingmuch).</description></item><item><title>The Iron Man talk from Nordic Perl Workshop</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-05-the-blogging-man-talk-from-nordic-perl-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-05-the-blogging-man-talk-from-nordic-perl-workshop/</guid><description>The NUUG Video group has finished the first video from the latest Nordic Perl Workshop, and sjn++ has put it online on the Oslo.pm blip.tv channel. It is Matt S Trout's Iron Man announcement from the lightning talks. Watch it in awe, then go Sign up for the program.</description></item><item><title>Interesting population numbers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-04-really-interesting-population-numbers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-05-04-really-interesting-population-numbers/</guid><description>Must read article that clears up some common myths about population growth and third world countries.
Perhaps the most striking fact about the demographic transformation now unfolding is that it is going to make the world look a lot more like Europe. The world is aging in an unprecedented way. A milepost in this process came in 1998, when for the first time the number of people in the developed world over the age of 60 outnumbered those below the age of 15.</description></item><item><title>Pictures from Nordic Perl Workshop</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-26-pictures-from-nordic-perl-workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-26-pictures-from-nordic-perl-workshop/</guid><description>Larry in sunset by Marcus Ramberg
Last week, we arranged Nordic Perl Workshop in Oslo. I've uploaded some pictures from the conference and the hackathon that was arranged at LinPro the weekend after. I've tagged all my photos with npw2009.</description></item><item><title>We Are Iron Man</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-22-we-are-iron-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-22-we-are-iron-man/</guid><description>Went to visit the Oslo rubyists today just to get the old worn out 'But we heard perl is dead', as a welcome. So worn out. Somehow they acknowledge that python is a nice language tho. So why has nobody heard from us in a while? Matt has a theory.
But here's my point: Perl people hang out on mailing lists. We bottom post, carefully interleaved, with 76 character lines. We have signatures that meet the McQ standard for acceptable size.</description></item><item><title>Diggbar is sleazy</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-15-diggbar-is-sleazy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-15-diggbar-is-sleazy/</guid><description>So, there has been a lot of noise about the diggbar lately. I think Ted Dziuba of Uncov fame says it best:
This move shows that not only is Digg willing to pull some sleazy shit to increase their unique visitors, but that they also need to pull this sleazy shit, because they need more unique visitors.</description></item><item><title>Dream job?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-15-dream-job/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-15-dream-job/</guid><description>Apparently Catalyst and DBIx::Class powers one of the biggest porn sites in the world, YouPorn:
We operate one of the most visited Catalyst/DBIx::Class sites in the world with 90 million users and hundreds of millions of pageviews per day. They are looking for contractors all over the world. No matter what you might think of the content, the stack they are using seems cool, pretty much the same libraries we use to power iusethis and our other sites.</description></item><item><title>Nordaaker's Services</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-07-nordaakers-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-07-nordaakers-services/</guid><description>In addition to our own web applications, Nordaaker provides various consulting services, mostly related to web development and Perl/Catalyst. We have just added a page describing those services to our home page. If you are interested in using our services, please send me an email. We are based in Oslo, Norway, but willing to travel/telecommute.</description></item><item><title>Worst use of Twitter Award</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-02-worst-use-of-twitter-award/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-02-worst-use-of-twitter-award/</guid><description>Goes to the gang at Macheist and Wil Shipley for their "spam all your twitter contacts and get delicious library for free" tweetblast. I fear this is just the beginning.
A strong runner-up
is @register_com, which seems to autoreply to anyone who mentions their service with a service notice [Posted with iBlogger from my iPhone]</description></item><item><title>Easy debugging of your Catalyst app</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-01-easy-debugging-of-your-catalyst-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-04-01-easy-debugging-of-your-catalyst-app/</guid><description>BigDiver shows us how to easily set up Komodo's remote debugging to work with Catalyst. If you don't like Komodo, you could also check out Leon's Devel::ebug, which actually has a Catalyst-based frontend.</description></item><item><title>Better documentation for complex classes</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-1692/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-1692/</guid><description>Jess Robinson writes:
Having been annoyed enough by this sort of POD wrangling already, theorbtwo came up with Pod::Inherit to help the module writers improve their documentation. Run it with the name of a class or the lib directory for your distribution, every class is investigated to determine which methods it contains, the inheritance tree is then searched to determine which base class actually defines that method. I think this is pretty awesome.</description></item><item><title>Consuming JSON with jquery</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-consuming-json-with-jquery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-consuming-json-with-jquery/</guid><description>When implementing twitter support in iusethis we used jQuery's awesome cross-domain JSON-P support to easily render your tweets about apps. The idea is that you tell jquery wh</description></item><item><title>Kon-Tiki Skull</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-kon-tiki-skull/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-31-kon-tiki-skull/</guid><description>Kon-Tiki Skull by Marcus Ramberg, originally uploaded by %2.
Took this while I was guide in Oslo for Jonas and Thomas from Metaquark. Metaquark is the label that created Appfresh.</description></item><item><title>MojoMojo now in FreeBSD ports.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-30-mojomojo-now-in-freebsd-ports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-30-mojomojo-now-in-freebsd-ports/</guid><description>After MojoMojo, the CMSish Wiki software that powers dev.catalyst.perl.org was featured prominently in the CPANTS Heavy 100, there was some concern about how much time was required to install it. However, thanks to the illustrious dane Lars Balker Rasmussen, FreeBSD guys now have it easy. He's fought through our entire dependency list, and uploaded p5-MojoMojo to the FreeBSD ports tree. Hopefully Debian packages won't be far behind. (In the interest of full disclosure, I am the founder of the MojoMojo project.</description></item><item><title>Using github's forking features.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-30-using-githubs-forking-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-30-using-githubs-forking-features/</guid><description>A few week back, I commented some concerns about git causing silos. I think this is a really good post by chris from github, illustrating the advantages of fully distributed development:
It may seem strange, and perhaps even like a lot of work. “Why should I have to check to see which is the most current? In the old model, there’s always a canonical repository.”
In the old model, actionwebservice wouldn’t have made it past 1.</description></item><item><title>A proper TryCatch for Perl</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-25-a-proper-trycatch-for-perl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-25-a-proper-trycatch-for-perl/</guid><description>While grown-up languages like Java has mechanisms to let you throw Exception objects, and to catch them in different places and do interesting things with them, most Perl code just dies with a error message of some sort (If you're lucky, it's even helpful, and reporting the mistake you did inside your own code, rather than going belly up inside the module itself. This is usually good enough for most people.</description></item><item><title>Awesome rubber band gun</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-24-awesome-rubber-band-gun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-24-awesome-rubber-band-gun/</guid><description>By Andy Mangold. Daddy, please make me one like that. And get me a pony while you're at it?</description></item><item><title>Airfoil Touch</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-22-airfoil-touch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-22-airfoil-touch/</guid><description>I'm a big fan of Rogue Amoeba's airfoil speakers, which make Apple's remote speaker functionality even more useful. Not quite sure when I'll</description></item><item><title>Facebook vanity URLs</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-22-facebook-vanity-urls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-22-facebook-vanity-urls/</guid><description>Chris has a interesting analysis of a recent move by Facebook to support username urls:
Arrington has a post that claims that "Facebook is getting wise to something MySpace has known from the start - users love vanity URLs."
I don’t buy it. In fact, I’m pretty sure that the omission of vanity URLs on Facebook is an intentional design decision from the beginning, and one that I’ve learned to appreciate over time.</description></item><item><title>7 principles for transforming difficult tasks into simple ones</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-17-7-principles-for-transforming-difficult-tasks-into-simple-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-17-7-principles-for-transforming-difficult-tasks-into-simple-ones/</guid><description>Here's another one of the talks from Nordic Perl Workshop 2006 that we're uploading as a promotion of Nordic Perl Workshop 2009. The conference is being held in Oslo again this year, April 16-17. I personally loved this talk by Michael Schwern, and it's not one that gets dated easily, so enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Easy remote branches with git</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-12-easy-remote-branches-with-git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-12-easy-remote-branches-with-git/</guid><description>Think remote branch management is a hassle with git? This nice ruby-based helper should sort you out:
$ sudo gem install git_remote_branch ... $ grb To get a quick explanation of how it works. Or read on at Git Ready</description></item><item><title>Balsamiq Mockups look awesome.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-balsamic-mockups-look-awesome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-balsamic-mockups-look-awesome/</guid><description>Go check out their screencast. I think $79 is a bit pricey for what it is tho.</description></item><item><title>Git results in silos?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-git-results-in-silos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-git-results-in-silos/</guid><description>Simon Wistow worries that the distributed nature of git results in fragmented software projects:
That model works well for Linux. Maybe. I'll presume it does. Git eases the pain points expressed by Andrew Morton, the maintainer of the -mm tree, in this message entitled "This Just Isn't Working Any More"
In short, it makes siloing easier.
My immediate reaction to reading his post was to think of the old saying ‹‹Guns don't kill people, people kill people››.</description></item><item><title>Monkey Island I remade as a Flash Movie</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-monkey-island-i-remade-as-a-flash-movie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-09-monkey-island-i-remade-as-a-flash-movie/</guid><description>Forgot some of the plot details of this classic adventure game? Get a quick and humorous reminder with this awesome flash movie. I just realized my two most memorable childhood games involve pirates and ninjas. Guess you can't go wrong with ninjas and pirates.</description></item><item><title>Why I'd rather not be an intellectual.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-08-why-id-rather-not-be-an-intellectual/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-08-why-id-rather-not-be-an-intellectual/</guid><description>An intellectual is a man who says a simple thing in a difficult way; an artist is a man who says a difficult thing in a simple way.
— Charles Bukowski</description></item><item><title>Catalyst-based StockTrader client</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-catalyst-based-stocktrader-client/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-catalyst-based-stocktrader-client/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Glaring omission from JSON Spec.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-glaring-omission-from-json-spec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-glaring-omission-from-json-spec/</guid><description>JSON has become a popular data-exchange format lately, and it's even been adopted as a config format by some. It's apparently useful for this, with an easily definable syntax, and fairly simple to understand for the en user. However, one factor that could hamper the adoption of JSON is the lack of comment support. This is a really strange omission. After all at JSON is really just a Javascript data structure, and JavaScript does support both the // and /* comment */ style.</description></item><item><title>Some positive Catalyst-feedback</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-some-positive-catalyst-feedback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-some-positive-catalyst-feedback/</guid><description>Chintana Wilamuna has recently tried out Catalyst for the Perl StockTrader client:
This time however, I had slightly more time available so I started from Catalyst::Manual::Tutorial and boy, the docs are amazingly well written. Kennedy Clark has done a wonderful job with the documentation.
Well deserved praise for Kennedy's work on the documentation. I think many people who tried out Catalyst in it's infancy don't realize how far the documentation has come since then.</description></item><item><title>The Hunt For The Apple Store Associates Program</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-the-hunt-for-the-apple-store-associates-program/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-06-the-hunt-for-the-apple-store-associates-program/</guid><description>As you might know, we run a software site for mac users, i use this. The site is free to use, and we finance it through the use of advertisments. Mostly we get advertisments from the Google ads program, as well as indie shareware developers, and occationally promotional programs like macheist.
I figure Apple Products would be a good fit for our users, so I was pleased when a quick Google Search turned up the Apple Store Associates Program.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing for performance.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-optimizing-for-performance-/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-optimizing-for-performance-/</guid><description>Thanks to mr. Gruber for linking to this really interesting acticle about performance policies in the WebKit project:
We have a zero-tolerance policy for performance regressions. If a patch lands that regresses performance according to our benchmarks, then the person responsible must either back the patch out of the tree or drop everything immediately and fix the regression.
As we've been working towards Catalyst 5.8, I think this is a test we need to get in place to ensure that 5.</description></item><item><title>Robots!</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-robots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-robots/</guid><description>I know I just posted about the big picture's carnival photos, but I can't resist linking to this post as well. Robots are just so awesome! I want the Tuba playing one.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia is a symbiosis</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-wikipedia-is-a-symbiosis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-05-wikipedia-is-a-symbiosis/</guid><description>Aaron Swartz has been taking a closer look at Wales' claims that Wikipedia is being written by a small group of people.
When you put it all together, the story become clear: an outsider makes one edit to add a chunk of information, then insiders make several edits tweaking and reformatting it. In addition, insiders rack up thousands of edits doing things like changing the name of a category across the entire site — the kind of thing only insiders deeply care about.</description></item><item><title>Big oops for Spotify?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-04-big-oops-for-spotify/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-04-big-oops-for-spotify/</guid><description>I just received a mail from Spotify about a security issue:
Along with passwords, registration information such as your email
address,birth date, gender, postal code and billing receipt
details were potentially exposed. Credit card numbers are not
stored by us and were not at risk. All payment data is handled
by a secure 3rd party provider. Oh well. At least they hashed our passwords and secured the credit card transactions.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Hacker News</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-04-lessons-from-hacker-news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-04-lessons-from-hacker-news/</guid><description>Graham writes about lessons from Hacker News, his social news site for nerds. Interesting for anyone who works with user-driven content.</description></item><item><title>An awesome error page</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-01-an-awesome-error-page/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-03-01-an-awesome-error-page/</guid><description>Wulffmorgenthaler is one of the web comics I follow religiously through my feed reader. The other day their comic didn't want to load. I tried following the link to their page, only to be presented with One of the coolest error pages I've seen. Of course, we all strive to keep our sites up 24/7. Still I think it is a sign of greatness to be able to put a smile on the lips of your readers even when your service your service is down.</description></item><item><title>What's next for Google Chrome</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-26-whats-next-for-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-26-whats-next-for-google-chrome/</guid><description>"If you look at the history of JavaScript it was originally designed to do things like have a pushable button, but it moved beyond that to become what nobody expected; namely a programming language for web applications.
I believe that with the current race to improve javascript performance, JS stands a good chance of being the language to use both on the server and the client in the near future.</description></item><item><title>iPhone sync for linux</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-25-iphone-sync-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-25-iphone-sync-for-linux/</guid><description>With the newer iPhone/iPod firmware, Apple has been doing their best to lock out the Linux people and other 3. parties that want to modify the iPhone database. Of course, these crafty hackers did not take it lying down, but have figured out a way around this. Come on Apple, you already know DRM doesn't work, don't you? I figured that was why you want out of it on the iTunes store.</description></item><item><title>Last Ninja on the WII</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-last-ninja-on-the-wii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-last-ninja-on-the-wii/</guid><description>Nintendo has started offering C64 titles on the WII, and one of the launch titles are one of my all time favorite games, The Last Ninja. I just spent way too much time getting through that swamp. If you don't know what it's all about, you can check out this long play video.
Another launch title is International Karate, which was arguably my first exposure to Versus Fighting Games, a category that have consumed more of my time than any others, with game series like Street Fighter and Tekken.</description></item><item><title>More reasons to love Twirc</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-more-reasons-to-love-twirc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-more-reasons-to-love-twirc/</guid><description>15:18 Wives and girlfriends around the world rejoice at Safari 4's Top Sites feature. #privatebrowsingtotherescue 15:20 favorite mattgemmell 15:20 Which tweet? 15:20 [1] Wives and girlfriends around the world rejoice at Safari ... 15:20 [2] @mattfarrugia Which podcast? 15:20 [3] @Zyote They were just in-case-of-no-beans backups, and I ... 15:20 1 15:20 -tweeter:&amp;twitter- favorite added For those who missed my previous post about Twirc, you can get it through CPAN or Github.</description></item><item><title>Painless rollouts with FCGI::Engine</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-painless-rollouts-with-fcgiengine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-24-painless-rollouts-with-fcgiengine/</guid><description>Our software site i use this is built on the MVC Framework Catalyst. We currently run it using the Russian web server Nginx and standalone fastcgi servers. I am using the Moose based CGI::Engine distribution by Stevan Little to start the servers. This module makes it really easy to manage your applications. You just create a YML config file like this:
--- - name: "iusethis-osx.server" nproc: 4 scriptname: "/www/iusethis-osx/script/iusethis_fastcgi.pl" pidfile: "</description></item><item><title>Carnivals around the world</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-23-carnivals-around-the-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-23-carnivals-around-the-world/</guid><description>These awesome, burlesque pictures from Big Picture makes me want to order a plane ride to Brazil right now. They just don't celebrate things that way around here.</description></item><item><title>linkhack - a smarter search?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-linkhack-a-smarter-search/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-linkhack-a-smarter-search/</guid><description>The search dropdown feature of firefox has never been one of my favorite features. It just takes too long to switch between them, so I've mostly left it at google, and hoped it would be smart enough to understand what I mean. However, with linkhack, it just proxies through to google most of the time, but understands keywords such as 'imdb' to do a movie search, or 'img' to do a image search.</description></item><item><title>sunday cuteness</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-sunday-cuteness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-sunday-cuteness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>sunday cuteness overload</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-sunday-cuteness-overload/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-22-sunday-cuteness-overload/</guid><description>Because the intarweb will never get tired of cute animals.</description></item><item><title>Perl.org dns broken</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-21-perlorg-dns-broken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-21-perlorg-dns-broken/</guid><description>Looks like DirectI/resellerclub (the domain registrar) decided to suspend perl.org! I've no idea why. They're not a communicative bunch. Also, nice touch doing it on a Saturday. For now, if you need access to search.cpan.org, you can reach it directly by ip: http://207.115.101.144/ Also, note that you can access the catalyst framework home page through http://www.catalystframework.org/. You can read more about it from Ask's blog.
*update* perl.org is back, serenity has been restored to the world.</description></item><item><title>pwn!youtube and all that jazz</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-21-pwnyoutube-and-all-that-jazz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-21-pwnyoutube-and-all-that-jazz/</guid><description>Want to download that youtube video you saw to your hard drive? Now you can. simply add 'pwn' to the hostname in the url. pwnyoutube.com provides both flv and mpeg4 downloads (when available from youtube). If you prefer, you can also use a bookmarklet. Using this service, I have added a download link to all youtube videos on our video bookmarking service iwatchthis.
I find it interesting that streaming copyrighted material seems more acceptable to old media than straight downloads.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-20-992/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-20-992/</guid><description>Some forbidden love is more interesting than others</description></item><item><title>Adobe UI Gripes</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-20-adobe-ui-gripes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-20-adobe-ui-gripes/</guid><description>Do not meddle in the affairs of designers, for they are subtle and quick to anger. Adobe has been getting a lot of shit lately, first their installers, and now this.</description></item><item><title>Markdown is different</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-18-markdown-is-different/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-18-markdown-is-different/</guid><description>David Wheeler says
Lately I’ve been fiddling a bit with Markdown, John Gruber’s minimalist plain text markup syntax. I’ve become more and more attracted to Markdown after I’ve had to spend some time using Trac and, to a lesser degree, Twiki and MediaWiki. The plain-text markup syntax in these projects is…how shall I put this?… gawdawful
This is a big part of the reason why we chose Markdown along with Textile as the supported Wiki markup languages for MojoMojo.</description></item><item><title>must-read essay from Doctorow</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-18-must-read-essay-from-doctorow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-18-must-read-essay-from-doctorow/</guid><description>I think we should permanently cut off the internet access of any company that sends out three erroneous copyright notices. Three strikes and you're out, mate.
Cory Doctorow is one of those people who brings out my inner fan boy. I could not agree more with his writing if I tried. If you haven't, I recommend checking out his books as well, they are freely available on the internet, or you can buy them at Amazon if you prefer hard copies.</description></item><item><title>Fixing project search in Textmate</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-17-fixing-project-search-in-textmate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-17-fixing-project-search-in-textmate/</guid><description>Hopefully you know about ack, Andy's super-handy Perl-based grep-on-steroids. I've been using it for a while in Textmate</description></item><item><title>New-wave Perl</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-17-new-wave-perl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-17-new-wave-perl/</guid><description>I was positively surprised by the response of the perl community. It wasn’t the typical “our programs run fast” (to ruby fanboys*) or “space as syntax wtf?” (to python fanboys). Instead it seemed that community took notice of the criticisms and made pretty clear that waiting for Perl 6 was not an option. Today, Perl 6 is doing fine (you can write code in Perl 6) and so is Perl 5.</description></item><item><title>Latest OSX Security upgrade can break your Perl</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-16-latest-osx-security-upgrade-can-break-your-perl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-16-latest-osx-security-upgrade-can-break-your-perl/</guid><description>Apple has shipped a somewhat untested security update, it seems. After installing it, my Catalyst apps stopped working in development. Trying to reinstall some modules through the CPAN shell brought further misery. Luckily, Miyagawa had already posted a solution to the CPAN problem. In addition, it seems they have installed a broken Scalar::Utils, so after following his advice and installing IO manually to get a unbroken CPAN shell, I suggest running</description></item><item><title>What really happened to magnolia?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-16-what-really-happened-to-magnolia-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-16-what-really-happened-to-magnolia-/</guid><description>Executive summary: Just taking a backup isn't always enough. You also need to test it.</description></item><item><title>Automatic deployment with Catalyst and Git</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-automatic-deployment-with-catalyst-and-git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-automatic-deployment-with-catalyst-and-git/</guid><description>Mike Nachbaur has written a description of how he deploys his Catalyst-based site to production using git and catalyst, while autoupdating dependencies and ensuring that his tests har run successfully. We currently deploy iusethis in a similar fashion, although a little bit more manually, and with a staging server to test larger rollouts.</description></item><item><title>Install modules via the CPAN shell from github</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-install-modules-via-the-cpan-shell-from-github/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-install-modules-via-the-cpan-shell-from-github/</guid><description>Nice hack by Miyagawa. I'd prefer if Perl continued to have a distributed delivery mechanism tho :-)</description></item><item><title>Perl community not generating any internal buzz?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-perl-community-not-generating-any-internal-buzz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-perl-community-not-generating-any-internal-buzz/</guid><description>Chromatic points to a trend in the Perl community of not giving any link love to our own. Somehow, it feels like I've heard this before. I agree this is a negative trend, but I find it amusing that it comes from chromatic, the only posters I can remember him linking to in his journal is people spreading FUD about Perl, in is mission to refute their statements. Somehow it seems to me like linking to these people and giving them attention is only making them stronger.</description></item><item><title>Perl Magick. Dark or white? You decide</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-perl-magick-dark-or-white-you-decide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-15-perl-magick-dark-or-white-you-decide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evil Empire in training</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-evil-empire-in-training/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-evil-empire-in-training/</guid><description>I think this is a pretty clear example of Apple showing their true color. They are not interested in openness or right or wrong, good or evil. Apple has only one interest, and that is generating more revenue for Apple. In fact, their attitude casts doubts on Google's "Do no evil" policy merely by their close association to Apple.
Clearly, Crackulous put Apple in a difficult position, and this is their attempt at solving it with one great swipe of the DMCA-Axe.</description></item><item><title>Javascript Uri object</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-javascript-uri-object/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-javascript-uri-object/</guid><description>Need to deal with Uris in a structured way in your client side code? This project is inspired by the Perl URI class, which is the defacto way of manipulating Resource Identifiers in Perl.</description></item><item><title>Paradox of choice or just lack of good defaults?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-paradox-of-choice-or-just-lack-of-good-defaults-/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-paradox-of-choice-or-just-lack-of-good-defaults-/</guid><description>So, a basic philosophy that Catalyst adopted from Perl itself is the famous There is more than one way to do it. Dan points out the fallacy of having to make too many choices when adopting a new framework. I disagree that that is a deciding factor in Rails or django having more web applications listed on appliedstack than Catalyst. I believe the extreme Rails hyping and number of books coming out to be a critical Rails success factor, and Google choosing Django as it's only language for App Engine to be a critical Django one.</description></item><item><title>Problems with star ratings</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-problems-with-star-ratings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-14-problems-with-star-ratings/</guid><description>Steven Frank points to some of the issues with star ratings. There are others, but in general this is part of why we decided to go another way with iusethis.</description></item><item><title>Good advice from mr. Gruber for budding iPhone developers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</guid><description>Want to implement anti-piracy mechanisms in your new iPhone app? I agree with most these recommendations for ways of dealing with this issue. However, I think that blocking all jailbroken phones would be a big mistake.</description></item><item><title>Using rebase with git pull</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-using-rebase-with-git-pull/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-12-using-rebase-with-git-pull/</guid><description>Great tip about using rebase when you pull from remote to get a cleaner git commit timeline.</description></item><item><title>MojoMojo is the heaviest app on CPAN :)</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-11-mojomojo-is-the-heaviest-app-on-cpan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-11-mojomojo-is-the-heaviest-app-on-cpan/</guid><description>Adam Kennedy has released the Heaviest modules on CPAN list, showing that MojoMojo is currently the application with the biggest dependency graph on CPAN. This proves that we are firm opponents of the "Not Invented Here"-syndrome. :) I've volunteered lbr to do the FreeBSD packages, anyone interested in packaging it for debian? Feel free to contact me.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from distributed software development</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-10-lessons-from-distributed-software-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-10-lessons-from-distributed-software-development/</guid><description>I found this very interesting, and some of his experiences rang very true to me. Nordaaker's experiences with distributed software development so far has been fairly positive, but it does require a different mind set. In particular I do agree that followers of agile software development will have to adjust. On think that I absolutely agree with but find it hard to sell in to clients is the 'do not estimate' policy.</description></item><item><title>Adding smooth keyboard navigation to your site using javascript and jQuery.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-adding-keyboard-navigation-for-your-site-with-jquery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-adding-keyboard-navigation-for-your-site-with-jquery/</guid><description>One of Arne's long-standing wishes for our video bookmarking site iwatchthis.com has been proper keyboard navigation. Today I finally found some tuits, and Just Fucking Did It. Turns out that with a couple of javascript libraries, it was surprisingly easy. Step one was the keyboard shortcuts library, which let you hook up to keyboard input in this simple fashion:
shortcut('up',function() { alert('Lucy in the sky with diamonds'); }) However, rather than bore you further you with Beatles lyrics, I hooked it up to the excellent scrollTo jQuery extension, which lets you smoothly scroll to any anchor in in the page (I added anchors into the video item for convenience):</description></item><item><title>Lucasarts Posters.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-lucasarts-posters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-lucasarts-posters/</guid><description>If you are anything like me, a large part of your misspent youth occured in front of a monitor, playing various games. For me and many of my friends the best games ever were Monkey Island and other Lucasarts adventure games. If that was the case for you, I'm sure you be excited at this opportunity to print and frame your very own fullsize Lucasarts game poster! Now I just need to convince my S.</description></item><item><title>Only a few days until epoch aligns</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-only-a-few-days-until-epoch-aligns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-09-only-a-few-days-until-epoch-aligns/</guid><description>Any geek worth his salt knows about the epoch time, the number of seconds since 1970-1-1 00:00. Seems we're approaching a pretty cool epoch in a few days. This is really an epoch win!</description></item><item><title>Definitive</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-something-interesting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-something-interesting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Definitively interesting</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-definitively-interesting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-definitively-interesting/</guid><description>Seems Matt and Kieren has got something interesting going on. Now we really need to get Catalyst 5.8 out there :-)</description></item><item><title>Hacking business models</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-hacking-business-models/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-hacking-business-models/</guid><description>Zak Greant, the original Mysql hacker has done some serious thinking about business models for small hacker companies. This is definitively something that Nordaaker needs to deal with, if we are to grow beyond our current small numbers. I really like these thoughts compared to the thinking I've met in most traditional companies. They seem more suited to modern technology workers.</description></item><item><title>Jesse Vincent talks about Request Tracker at NPW</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-jesse-vincent-talks-about-request-tracker-at-npw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-08-jesse-vincent-talks-about-request-tracker-at-npw/</guid><description>(this video is from a weekly series that we are uploading from Nordic Perl Workshop 2006 to promote the upcoming Nordic Perl Workshop 2009)
I've used Request Tracker for many years. It's a terrific tool for keeping track of customer requests. With the latest versions, it even looks good.</description></item><item><title>Moose slides from Frozen Perl</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-moose-slides-from-frozen-perl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-moose-slides-from-frozen-perl/</guid><description>The Frozen Perl conference is going on in Minneapolis this weekend. For those of us who missed it, I think these slides by Shawn M. Moore are worth checking out. A good introduction to Moose, and the best Method Modifier examples I've seen.</description></item><item><title>Prettify your flickr stream with «I Hardly Knew Her»</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-prettify-your-flickr-stream-with-i-hardly-knew-her/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-prettify-your-flickr-stream-with-i-hardly-knew-her/</guid><description>I have to say, I think this alternative flickr interface is just great. It gives focus to the photos, while providing exactly enough metadata (hint: click the picture to view large version). I've linked up my flickr stream here, to see your own, just change the username in the url.</description></item><item><title>Ryan Air reaches new levels of customer hostility</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-ryan-air-reaches-new-levels-of-customer-hostility/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-ryan-air-reaches-new-levels-of-customer-hostility/</guid><description>That's it. I'm officially never going to fly with Ryan Air again, no matter the price difference.</description></item><item><title>The death of web 2.0 innocence?</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-the-death-of-web-20-innocence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-07-the-death-of-web-20-innocence/</guid><description>Our friend Chris Messina was closer to the death of ma.gnolia than most of us, having worked for them as a consultant, as well as having a close relationship with the site owner. He writes with great insight about how this has affected him personally, as well as the lessons he sees for web 2.0.
The thing I don't get about the whole deal is "Why were there no backups?". I've yet to hear any explanations.</description></item><item><title>Parsing Postgresql version numbers</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-06-parsing-postgresql-version-numbers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-06-parsing-postgresql-version-numbers/</guid><description>Magnus Hagander gives a good explanation of how the Postgresql versioning scheme works.</description></item><item><title>Disney's Robin Hood - Oo De Lally in various languages</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-dinseys-robin-hood-oo-de-lally-in-various-languages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-dinseys-robin-hood-oo-de-lally-in-various-languages/</guid><description>Andy Baio continues to find interesting uses of the technology that has become available to us lately. I was able to contribute by finding the Norwegian version :-)</description></item><item><title>Happy to see that Perl is getting some love from the mac crowd</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-happy-to-see-that-perl-is-getting-some-love-from-the-mac-crowd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-happy-to-see-that-perl-is-getting-some-love-from-the-mac-crowd/</guid><description>Seen in my twitter feed:
22:35 @mjtsai Heh - I had high hopes for python, but ... 22:35 perl -e "" 0.00s user 22:35 ruby -e "" 0.01s user 22:35 python -c "" 0.08s user 22:40 @danielpunkass Infinitely slower than Perl! In case you were wondering, Daniel and Michael were discussing this post from @gruber.</description></item><item><title>Vaxy</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-vaxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-vaxy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why your avatar matters</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-why-your-avatar-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-05-why-your-avatar-matters/</guid><description>Good article about Avatars. As we continue to build our internet personalities, branding gets more and more important. Wonder if I should add an avatar to the sidebar of this blog?
I tend to switch between a Self portrait I took while Photographing ABC Startsiden and my Manga me (From Face your manga). I feel that both of them work, as the manga one is quite recognizable), but I would love to get a good hand-drawn one, as I feel the manga ones are a bit generic.</description></item><item><title>eg makes it really easy for svn users to switch to git</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-eg-makes-it-really-easy-for-svn-users-to-switch-to-git/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-eg-makes-it-really-easy-for-svn-users-to-switch-to-git/</guid><description>Are you trying to sell in git to your colleagues, who are afraid of learning anything new? easy git might be the ticket to convince them. Check out the side-by-side comparison on how to do things in svn and eg</description></item><item><title>Flash version of the awesome arcade game QIX</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-flash-version-of-the-awesome-arcade-game-qix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-flash-version-of-the-awesome-arcade-game-qix/</guid><description>Good remake of this classic.</description></item><item><title>Moose docs get a serious overhaul</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-moose-docs-get-a-serious-overhaul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-04-moose-docs-get-a-serious-overhaul/</guid><description>Thanks to the Perl Foundation, who sponsored Dave Rolsky's work to write a Moose manual. There is now no good excuse for not knowing what the Moose offers :) Check it out at search.cpan.org</description></item><item><title>Advanced Javascript debugging</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-advanced-javascript-debugging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-advanced-javascript-debugging/</guid><description>Good article from alistapart showing a good workflow for debugging your javascript code with firebug and other available tools.</description></item><item><title>Another catalyst</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-another-catalyst/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-another-catalyst/</guid><description>I actually like their logo better than ours.</description></item><item><title>The ironically named window manager</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-the-ironically-named-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-03-the-ironically-named-window-manager/</guid><description>overheard in catalyst developer channel
11:53 awesome-- # wasting half an hour to port the config file after every upgrade isn't fun Crap like this makes me so happy to be a mac user.</description></item><item><title>Benchmarking Perl by Gisle Aas</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-benchmarking-perl-by-gisle-aas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-benchmarking-perl-by-gisle-aas/</guid><description>From Nordic Perl Workshop 2006. Check out more videos at the Oslo.pm channel</description></item><item><title>Fisherman at Huk</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-fisherman-at-huk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-fisherman-at-huk/</guid><description>Fishing, originally uploaded by Marcus Ramberg. We went out to huk for a walk on sunday. Follow the link to Flickr to see some more photos from there.</description></item><item><title>Tweeting from irssi with twirc</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-tweeting-from-irssi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-02-tweeting-from-irssi/</guid><description>When I started out with twitter, I used the native OSX client Twitterrific. It's a pretty nice piece of software, but I couldn't get comfortable with it popping up every time there was a new tweet, as it was a bit too disturbing, and if I turned it off, I forgot to check it out at all.
However, lately, I have a much better solution. I already communicate fairly frequently through the venerable Internet Relay Chat protocol (or IRC as most people know it).</description></item><item><title>Accessing your Catalyst config from scripts</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-catalyst_config_from_scripts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-catalyst_config_from_scripts/</guid><description>Often, I need to write command line scripts that access my apps' data models. With Catalyst, one way to do this is to to load the actual application, like
use iusethis; Then I can access my models like iusethis-&amp;gt;model('DBIC::Person') . However, all I really need is to get the application configuration, and loading a big application is a lot of overhead. Just using Config::Any isn't a good solution tho, since it does not handle _local files properly, among other thing.</description></item><item><title>Joose 2.0 released</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-joose-20-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-joose-20-released/</guid><description>Joose, the javascript meta object system inspired by Moose recently released version 2.0 of their framework adding support for offical support for types/sub types as well as coercisons. There are also a bunch of other changes, read on at the original announcement. You can also check out the project homepage.</description></item><item><title>‹‹A vampire story›› now out for the mac.</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-%e2%80%b9%e2%80%b9a-vampire-story%e2%80%ba%e2%80%ba-now-out-for-the-mac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-02-01-%e2%80%b9%e2%80%b9a-vampire-story%e2%80%ba%e2%80%ba-now-out-for-the-mac/</guid><description>Too bad the the game is plagued by the most annoying sense of humor ever. I suggest getting World of Goo instead if you are looking for a new game to play on your mac.</description></item><item><title>Daily perl onliner on twitter</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-31-daily-perl-onliner-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-31-daily-perl-onliner-on-twitter/</guid><description>Get a useful perl one-liner every day in your tweets.</description></item><item><title>Löve is a 2d game engine, which seems pretty awesome</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-31-love-is-a-2d-game-engine-which-seems-pretty-awesome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-31-love-is-a-2d-game-engine-which-seems-pretty-awesome/</guid><description>So awesome, in fact, that I will have to try to learn LUA. @Arne, let's make QIX for osx? :)</description></item><item><title>Cleaning up after FastCGI</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-cleaning-up-after-fastcgi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-cleaning-up-after-fastcgi/</guid><description>If you have any apps running under FastCGI, you know the error logs it outputs are quite messy. Hobbs shows a nice technique for cleaning up this mess.</description></item><item><title>Creating a standalone Damon with Moose and friends</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-creating-a-standalone-damon-with-moose-and-friends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-creating-a-standalone-damon-with-moose-and-friends/</guid><description>I recently needed to create a persistent daemon to do some maintenance tasks for iusethis. Turns out that building these with the postmodern object system Moose is really easy.
For those of you not in the know, Moose has the concept of 'Roles', stolen from the Perl 6 project. Roles work kind of like a mix-in that you can add to your class to make it super powerful :) (For the extra curious, you can read more details about Roles in Perl6 here).</description></item><item><title>Ice fishing hole</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-ice-fishing-hole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-30-ice-fishing-hole/</guid><description>Ice fiishing hole, originally uploaded by Marcus Ramberg.</description></item><item><title>Lisp programmer declaring Perl to be a "beautiful, wonderfully designed language"</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-29-lisp-programmer-declaring-perl-to-be-a-beautyful-wonderfully-designed-language/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-29-lisp-programmer-declaring-perl-to-be-a-beautyful-wonderfully-designed-language/</guid><description>I did not see that one coming.</description></item><item><title>Oslo Perl Mongers blip.tv channel</title><link>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-29-oslo-perl-mongers-bliptv-channel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2009-01-29-oslo-perl-mongers-bliptv-channel/</guid><description>See videos from Nordic Perl Workshop 2006.</description></item></channel></rss>