<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ios on marcus</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/ios/</link><description>Recent content in ios on marcus</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 19:54:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goodbye 182 day streak</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-08-04-goodbye-182-day-streak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 19:54:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-08-04-goodbye-182-day-streak/</guid><description>Today I’m ending my love affair with duolingo, have just signed up for a year of memrise. Let’s see if I can finally git gud at Russian :)</description></item><item><title>Apple tightening the screws on web service developers</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/apple-tightening-the-screws-on-web-service-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/apple-tightening-the-screws-on-web-service-developers/</guid><description>Wow. I&amp;#39;m literally stunned. Apple just doubled down on their rejection of HEY&amp;#39;s ability to provide bug fixes and new features, unless we submit to their outrageous demand of 15-30% of our revenue. Even worse: We&amp;#39;re told that unless we comply, they&amp;#39;ll REMOVE THE APP.
&amp;mdash; DHH (@dhh) June 16, 2020 Apparently the rule is now that you cannot have any app related to a paid web service, unless you allow the user to subscribe through the App Store, and give Apple 30%.</description></item><item><title>RoutineHub</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/routinehub/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/routinehub/</guid><description>Looking for more shortcuts for your iOS device? RoutineHub seems to be the best collection out there.</description></item><item><title>Post to Hugo from ios with Editorial and Working Copy</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick workflow to post to a Hugo blog on the go using Editorial and Working Copy.</description></item><item><title>beorg - org mode on the go</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</guid><description>One of the big reasons I finally succumbed to the Evil side was the search for a comprehensive notes and todo system.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing many approaches, like Taskwarrior and Workflowy, but org-mode is by far the best I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far.
In 2020 mobile is a critical component for such a system, and thus beorg was an important part of that decision. It&amp;rsquo;s an impressive piece of software, implementing all the important features of org mode like syncing, all aspects of sheduling and repeats , custom todo states and a comprehensive parser.</description></item><item><title>NoOps is an awful word</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</guid><description>What do IT Ops do? We manage IT risk on behalf of the business. Thinking Ops is about servers is like thinking Dev is about code cutting.
If you think devops means eliminating operations, you don&amp;rsquo;t understand development or operations.</description></item><item><title>Testing posts from ios</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</guid><description>This post is a quick test to see if I can easily post to my blog from Working Copy and Textastic. It is still a little beta, but it seems very promising!</description></item><item><title>Don't animate scrollTo of the body on iOS.</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</guid><description>Animate body.offsetTop and body.offsetLeft works great on the desktop, but is hugely buggy on MobileSafari. Instead, make a viewport div that fills the screen, and animate the offset on that.
I hope this helps someone, as I spent 3 hours figuring it out.</description></item><item><title>Onion browser - TOR on IOS</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-04-30-onion-browser-tor-on-ios/</guid><description>The Onion Router is a internet project that aims to anonymize your traffic by routing it through a darknet with various exit points to the Internet. Normally you would have to install a browser proxy on your machine to access TOR, but now there's a browser available for the iPad and iPhone.
Of course, I had to test it by checking out the Silk Road, a much publicized "Amazon of illegal drugs"</description></item><item><title>3 reasons for the lack of updates here lately</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2010-08-06-3-reasons-for-the-lack-of-updates-here-lately/</guid><description> Dark Nebula Episode 2 Gravity Hook Van Helsing</description></item><item><title>How to build a offine HTML5 iphone app</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2010-03-28-how-to-build-a-offine-html5-iphone-app/</guid><description>I need to look into this for the iusethis iPhone application. The launch time is one thing that annoys me with that app now, and this could be a good way to sort that out.</description></item><item><title>Tab bar or no Tab bar?</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</guid><description>Interesting writeup from Justin Williams about the use of Tab Bars in iPhone development. One of his big gripes is related to the space the tabbar uses:
When I made the decision, my thinking was that the application had four separate features, so it only made sense to separate them using the tab bar. What I found as I got further into the development of the application was that the bottom tab bar was incredibly limiting for where to place extra controls.</description></item><item><title>Diary of an app store reviewer</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-05-30-diary-of-an-app-store-reviewer/</guid><description>Gruber has written a brilliant guess at what must be going on inside the heads of the Apple App Store reviewers' mind. I specially enjoyed this nugget:
I could read that over and over. It’s like the voice of a robot. The voice of authority. The voice of authoritative robots.</description></item><item><title>Good advice from mr. Gruber for budding iPhone developers</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-02-12-good-advice-from-mr-gruber-for-budding-iphone-developers/</guid><description>Want to implement anti-piracy mechanisms in your new iPhone app? I agree with most these recommendations for ways of dealing with this issue. However, I think that blocking all jailbroken phones would be a big mistake.</description></item></channel></rss>