<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ios on Suburban Nerd</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/ios/</link><description>Recent content in ios on Suburban Nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.nordaaker.com/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple tightening the screws on web service developers</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/apple-tightening-the-screws-on-web-service-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/apple-tightening-the-screws-on-web-service-developers/</guid><description>Apparently the rule is now that you cannot have any app related to a paid web service, unless you allow the user to subscribe through the App Store, and give Apple 30%. No matter if you provide links to your site or allow signing up in the app.
I wonder if this would still apply if you provide an open source version of your app, but also a paid service for that same open source app?</description></item><item><title>Post to Hugo from ios with Editorial and Working Copy</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/hugo-editorial-workflow/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick workflow to post to a Hugo blog on the go using Editorial and Working Copy.</description></item><item><title>beorg - org mode on the go</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/beorg-org-mode-on-the-go/</guid><description>One of the big reasons I finally succumbed to the Evil side was the search for a comprehensive notes and todo system.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing many approaches, like Taskwarrior and Workflowy, but org-mode is by far the best I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far.
In 2020 mobile is a critical component for such a system, and thus beorg was an important part of that decision. It&amp;rsquo;s an impressive piece of software, implementing all the important features of org mode like syncing, all aspects of sheduling and repeats , custom todo states and a comprehensive parser.</description></item><item><title>NoOps is an awful word</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-06-noops-must-die/</guid><description>What do IT Ops do? We manage IT risk on behalf of the business. Thinking Ops is about servers is like thinking Dev is about code cutting.
If you think devops means eliminating operations, you don&amp;rsquo;t understand development or operations.</description></item><item><title>Testing posts from ios</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2015-01-05-posting-to-github-pages-from-ios/</guid><description>This post is a quick test to see if I can easily post to my blog from Working Copy and Textastic. It is still a little beta, but it seems very promising!</description></item><item><title>Don't animate scrollTo of the body on iOS.</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/2012-07-11-dont-animate-scrollto-of-the-body-on-ios/</guid><description>Animate body.offsetTop and body.offsetLeft works great on the desktop, but is hugely buggy on MobileSafari. Instead, make a viewport div that fills the screen, and animate the offset on that.
I hope this helps someone, as I spent 3 hours figuring it out.</description></item><item><title>RoutineHub</title><link>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/routinehub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.nordaaker.com/post/routinehub/</guid><description>Looking for more shortcuts for your iOS device? RoutineHub seems to be the best collection out there.</description></item></channel></rss>