<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>homeautomation on marcus.means.no</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/homeautomation/</link><description>Recent content in homeautomation on marcus.means.no</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 20:54:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/homeautomation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I'm running Home Assistant in docker on NixOS</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-07-19-how-i-m-running-home-assistant-in-docker-on-nixos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 20:54:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-07-19-how-i-m-running-home-assistant-in-docker-on-nixos/</guid><description>For the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been into home automation, and since I buy random stuff from different vendors and with various protocols, I use Home Assistant to tie it all together. My main home server is a NixOS box, but for a long while I was running home assistant on my old Arch mac mini, because it was such a chore to handle dependencies with the NixOS home assistant service.</description></item><item><title>Home Assistant 0.112 released</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-07-01-home-assistant-0.112-released-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 23:10:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-07-01-home-assistant-0.112-released-/</guid><description>Always glad to see updates to my home automation system of choice. Performance improvements to logbook and history are much appreciated. I need to switch to the new z-wave integration soon.</description></item><item><title>Weekend Project: Z-wave controlled Solenoid valve for watering</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-06-21-weekend-project-z-wave-controlled-solenoid-valve-for-watering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2020-06-21-weekend-project-z-wave-controlled-solenoid-valve-for-watering/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a manual micro-drip system for our green house and flowers. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do something to automate watering schedules for our the micro drip system and our lawn and even ordered a solenoid valve from the internets a while back. It arrived a couple of weeks ago, and with a rainy sunday, I was finally ready to tackle this project.
Basically I just combined a z-wave light switch with the solenoid switch, stuffed it into a waterproof box and connected it to the water hose.</description></item></channel></rss>