<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on marcus . means . no</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on marcus . means . no</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code released under the Apache 2.0 license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcus.means.no/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Makers</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-05-07-makers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2012-05-07-makers/</guid><description>You can start making something in seconds.
One simple idea is all you need before your brain
automatically explores problems, solutions, and dreams.
Turning that idea into something tangible and wonderful is harder.
You need structure, strategies, people, hard work.
The software world is young and we are still figuring out the most basic processes of the craft. For instance, we tend to label ourself architects or designers, inspired by people who build houses or work in mass production.</description></item><item><title>Tab bar or no Tab bar?</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-07-09-tab-bar-or-no-tab-bar/</guid><description>Interesting writeup from Justin Williams about the use of Tab Bars in iPhone development. One of his big gripes is related to the space the tabbar uses:
When I made the decision, my thinking was that the application had four separate features, so it only made sense to separate them using the tab bar. What I found as I got further into the development of the application was that the bottom tab bar was incredibly limiting for where to place extra controls.</description></item><item><title>TextMate 2: It's coming</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-06-14-2517/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-06-14-2517/</guid><description>Allan Odgaard reassures us that TextMate 2 isn't going to be a Duke Nukem Forever:
So where does development stand for 2.0? It feels to me like most of the modules are getting close, say 90%. But as they say, on the horizon, mountains look small.
I guess he just has the remaining 90% to finish. :) I for one think this is exciting news. TextMate is probably my second most used program after Firefox.</description></item><item><title>GitHub:FI pricing now public</title><link>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-06-11-githubfi-pricing-now-public/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcus.means.no/post/2009-06-11-githubfi-pricing-now-public/</guid><description>GitHub created a headache for themselves at the initial launch of their inhouse hosting option for companies wanting to use GitHub.
That, coupled with the fact that we wanted companies to sign an NDA before receiving their quote, slowed the entire process down. It also bewildered more than a few people wondering why lawyers needed to be involved just to figure out how much the product cost.
Well, now they are up for everybody to see, but boy, with prices like that, I can see why they would like to keep them secret.</description></item></channel></rss>